<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>music on Dieter&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://dieter.plaetinck.be/tags/music/</link>
    <description>Recent content in music on Dieter&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2012 18:10:36 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/music/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Thailand, Berlin Velocity EU, NYC, Ghent and more metal</title>
      <link>http://dieter.plaetinck.be/post/thailand_berlin_velocity_nyc_ghent_metal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2012 18:10:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>thailand_berlin_velocity_nyc_ghent_metal</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt;Thailand&lt;/h3&gt;
In July I did a 3-week group journey through Thailand arranged by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.explorado.be&#34;&gt;Explorado&lt;/a&gt;, but organized by (&#34;outsourced to&#34;) the 2 guides of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rootsofasia.com/&#34;&gt;roots of Asia&lt;/a&gt;, who did &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rootsofasia.com/get-to-know-us/feedback.html&#34;&gt;an amazing job&lt;/a&gt;.
The whole concept was exploring &#34;the real Thailand&#34; by means of &lt;i&gt;Eco-tourism&lt;/i&gt;.  We&#39;ve been in Bangkok (twice), Chiang Mai city, a mountain village in the province of Chiang Mai, through the jungle, at a fisherman village in Phuket and at the tropical island of Koh Pha ngan.
The latter was at the end of the trip and was timed perfectly to get some deserved rest in a more touristy (although not too busy) area, but the majority of the trip was spent far away from the typical touristy areas so we could be submerged in honest, authentic Thai culture and visit authentic locations, often we were at locations where seeing a group of white folks is not common.
We&#39;ve been at unique authentic temples, stayed with various locals and hill tribes, shared meals with them, took the same transport they did (at one point an entire village collected their bikes so we could borrow them to do a bike trip through rice fields and some of the most beautiful lakes I&#39;ve ever seen).  We&#39;ve had plenty of beautiful moments during those 3 weeks.  Like visiting the home of one of the local Thai who built his entire house out of clay, by himself and some friends, or visiting the ancient temple where our guide got married, in a forest in the hills, it was the most beautiful temple of the entire trip, but no other tourists go there because it&#39;s not really known (and should probably be kept that way).  Or going to a bar in Chiang Mai city (one evening on my own, the next I brought a fellow traveler) to have some good times with some locals.
The Eco-conscious part of the travel means:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;green travel (minimize impact on the environment, &#34;leave no trace&#34;).  Other than taking the plane over there and back we did a pretty good job, we&#39;ve used public buses, night trains, biodegradable soap, etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;local foods (no import, minimal packaging, wrap in banana leaves, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;supporting Eco-conscious projects (like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.elephantnaturepark.org/&#34;&gt;elephant nature park&lt;/a&gt;, which is an entire volunteer-based reserve to give mistreated elephants (which has been a big problem in Thailand) a better life, where we washed and fed elephants)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
This has been a great experience, and although I found the culture in the South disgustingly based on profiting from tourists, and the cities are too polluted and dirty, I&#39;ve seen cultures so respectful of nature and each other, living by values I&#39;ve been trying to apply at home - but being frowned upon in our western society because we&#39;re so brainwashed by consumerism, which was beautiful and heartwarming.
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;!-- &lt;img src=&#34;http://dieter.plaetinck.be/files/thailand_jungle.jpg&#34; height=&#34;150px&#34;/&gt; --&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://dieter.plaetinck.be/files/thailand_elephant.jpg&#34; height=&#34;150px&#34;/&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://dieter.plaetinck.be/files/thailand_tree.jpg&#34; height=&#34;150px&#34;/&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://dieter.plaetinck.be/files/thailand_tribe.jpg&#34; height=&#34;150px&#34;/&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://dieter.plaetinck.be/files/thailand_gekko.jpg&#34; height=&#34;150px&#34;/&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://dieter.plaetinck.be/files/thailand_boat.jpg&#34; height=&#34;150px&#34;/&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://dieter.plaetinck.be/files/thailand_emblem.jpg&#34; height=&#34;150px&#34;/&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://dieter.plaetinck.be/files/thailand_hangmat.jpg&#34; height=&#34;150px&#34;/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.10150511397165279.397476.627030278&amp;type=1&amp;l=2e7844ab2b&#34;&gt;Photo album&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Berlin&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img style=&#34;float:left;margin:0 5px 0 0;&#34; src=&#34;http://dieter.plaetinck.be/files/berlin_velocity.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Berlin Velocity EU conference&#34; height=&#34;150px&#34;/&gt;
&lt;img style=&#34;float:left;margin:0 5px 0 0;&#34; src=&#34;http://dieter.plaetinck.be/files/berlin_reichstag.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Berlin Reichstag building&#34; height=&#34;150px&#34;/&gt;
I&#39;ve been in Berlin for the first &lt;a href=&#34;http://velocityconf.com/velocityeu/&#34;&gt;Velocity conference in the EU&lt;/a&gt;, which was quite good.  The best part was probably the &#34;Velocity Birds of feather&#34; (whatever that means) unconference the day before at &lt;a href=&#34;http://betahaus.de&#34;&gt;betahaus&lt;/a&gt;, which was great for meeting some folks such as the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.soundcloud.com&#34;&gt;soundcloud.com&lt;/a&gt; guys (which BTW, is the site we host our music on), although lots more interesting folks attended the conference itself (and it was packed).
Berlin itself was nice too.  Lots of history (Berlin wall, world war(s)), lots of impressive architecture (old and new), very cheap (albeit mediocre in quality) food, lots of Italian food, a bit cold though.

&lt;h3 style=&#34;clear: left;&#34;&gt;New York city&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img style=&#34;float:left;margin:0 5px 0 0;&#34; src=&#34;http://dieter.plaetinck.be/files/brooklyn_bridge.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Brooklyn bridge&#34; height=&#34;150px&#34;/&gt;
&lt;img style=&#34;float:left;margin:0 5px 0 0;&#34; src=&#34;http://dieter.plaetinck.be/files/manhattan_harbor.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Manhattan harbor&#34; height=&#34;150px&#34;/&gt;
I&#39;m still recovering from the awesome time I just had in NYC. I&#39;ve been way more busy over there than I anticipated. I should have stayed 2 or 3 weeks instead of 1 :).  I&#39;ve met various locals (one of whom who&#39;d love to become a city guide as 2nd job because she just loves showing people around, so that just turned out great!). I didn&#39;t go for the typical touristy things (I skipped things like the WTC memorial, empire state building, statue of liberty, to the extent you can skip them, as they are very visible from pretty much all over the place).
Instead, I wanted to get a feel of the real city and the people inhabiting it.  I&#39;ve seen parts of Queens, central and North-West Brooklyn, lots of areas (but not enough) in Manhattan and even Staten Island, been to a rock concert, comedy, improv and cabaret shows, the movies, more bars than I can count and mostly ate out with company (just as real new yorkers do, of course, though for breakfast that feels a bit weird).  I even went shopping (not mall-shopping, but groceries in the supermarket, the Williamsburg Foodtown - that&#39;s what it&#39;s called - clerk advised me to enjoy every last second in the US, phrased in a way as if any other place in the world sucks in comparison, which is ridiculous, but turns out I followed his advice anyway) because I stayed at an apartment in Williamsburg, I also had 2 roommates, with whom I ironically couldn&#39;t spend as much time as I wanted to as I was so busy meeting up with all those other people, I also visited the Etsy and Vimeo offices (both are awesome) and met up with Dave Reisner (who is one of our latest Arch Linux devs, and who lives in NJ, but don&#39;t tell anyone) and who forgot to show me around in the Google office ;-)  And I realize some of the past sentences are a bit long and busy but that&#39;s one of the things I learned at New York I guess.  For one week, I almost lived like a real New Yorker, and it was interesting (but exhausting).

&lt;h3 style=&#34;clear: left;&#34;&gt;Move to Ghent&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img style=&#34;float:left;margin:0 5px 0 0;&#34; src=&#34;http://dieter.plaetinck.be/files/ghent_bridge.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Ghent, bridge of Sint-Michiels&#34; height=&#34;150px&#34;/&gt;
&lt;img style=&#34;float:left;margin:0 5px 0 0;&#34; src=&#34;http://dieter.plaetinck.be/files/ghent_coupure.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Ghent, coupure&#34; height=&#34;150px&#34;/&gt;
Enough about the trips.  Back to daily life.  I moved to the city of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ghent&#34;&gt;Ghent&lt;/a&gt;.  Riding by bike to work every day along the scenic &lt;a href=&#34;http://nl.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coupure_%28Gent%29&#34;&gt;Coupure&lt;/a&gt; is fun.
I am quite proud to say nearly all of my stuff in this apartment is second hand and I&#39;ve been lucky to receive some free stuff as well (thanks Bram!).  Not (only) because I&#39;m &lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration:line-through&#34;&gt;cheap&lt;/span&gt; money conscious but I like to give things a second life instead of buying something new, lowering the impact on the environment. Even if it doesn&#39;t look too well, as long as it&#39;s functional.  And this is exactly one of those values I mentioned above which is often not understood in our Western society but I was pleased to find out this philosophy is the standard in large parts of Thai culture.

&lt;h3 style=&#34;clear: left;&#34;&gt;Death metal&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img style=&#34;float:left;margin:0 5px 0 0;&#34; src=&#34;http://dieter.plaetinck.be/files/li_promoshoot.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Promo shoot&#34; height=&#34;150px&#34;/&gt;
&lt;img style=&#34;float:left;margin:0 5px 0 0;&#34; src=&#34;http://dieter.plaetinck.be/files/li_frontline.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Live @ Frontline, Ghent&#34; height=&#34;150px&#34;/&gt;
We&#39;ve done 3 gigs (which had great reception, luckily) and we&#39;ve got planned a few already for 2012, one of which will be at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/pages/From-Rock-Till-Core/141364465969247&#34;&gt;From Rock Till Core festival&lt;/a&gt; in Merelbeke.
We also did a semi-professional &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lightbulbinferno.com/album_promoshoot_summer_2011&#34;&gt;photo-shoot&lt;/a&gt;, and I made a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lightbulbinferno.com/&#34;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; (you can tell I&#39;m not a designer).
&lt;br style=&#34;clear: left;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
That wraps up 2011 for me. Good times.. Happy new year everybody!
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My metal band</title>
      <link>http://dieter.plaetinck.be/post/my_metalband/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2011 14:58:12 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>my_metalband</guid>
      <description>&lt;img width=&#34;18%&#34; src=&#34;http://dieter.plaetinck.be/files/pdp3.jpg&#34; style=&#34;float: left; margin-right: 28px&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the audience of this blog is largely technical, I don&#39;t post much about other topics, but I feel it&#39;s time for a short summary about one of my &#34;real life projects&#34;.
&lt;br/&gt;In the spring of 2009 I joined a progressive death metal band.  I&#39;ve been drumming since I was 17, but during the last 2 years I&#39;ve been practising and rehearsing like never before.[1]
&lt;br/&gt;When you hear yourself on tape for the first time, it&#39;s a bit of disillusionment as you suddenly hear every imperfection, many of which you didn&#39;t realise you had (or didn&#39;t think were very noticeable).
&lt;br/&gt;So 2 years of practicing, rehearsing, test recordings, real recordings, mixing sessions (where you really grow a good ear towards imperfections) later we are now getting to the point where we can nail our stuff and are looking very forward to our first gig, which will be June 3rd in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jhsjatoo.org/&#34;&gt;jh sjatoo&lt;/a&gt; in Kalken.
We&#39;ve written about 7 songs, of which at this point we play 5. I wish we had proper recordings of all of them, but &#34;Total Annihilation&#34; captures several aspects of our style:
&lt;object height=&#34;225&#34; width=&#34;65%&#34;&gt; &lt;param name=&#34;movie&#34; value=&#34;http://player.soundcloud.com/player.swf?url=http%3A%2F%2Fapi.soundcloud.com%2Fusers%2F2762471&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name=&#34;allowscriptaccess&#34; value=&#34;always&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;embed allowscriptaccess=&#34;always&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; src=&#34;http://player.soundcloud.com/player.swf?url=http%3A%2F%2Fapi.soundcloud.com%2Fusers%2F2762471&#34; type=&#34;application/x-shockwave-flash&#34; width=&#34;65%&#34;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt; &lt;/object&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;In early 2010 I treated myself (found a nice 2nd hand deal) to a new pdp birch kit with Zildjian Z custom cymbals (that was actually at the time I was in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://dieter.plaetinck.be/not_working_for_facebook.html&#34;&gt;interview process for a Palo-Alto position at Facebook&lt;/a&gt; so I might have needed to sell it again soon after, but that didn&#39;t happen).
&lt;br/&gt; Here are some pics:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://dieter.plaetinck.be/files/pdp1.jpg&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://dieter.plaetinck.be/files/pdp2.jpg&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://dieter.plaetinck.be/files/pdp3.jpg&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://dieter.plaetinck.be/files/pdp4.jpg&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;.
More info about the band:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/lightbulbinferno&#34;&gt;Lightbulb Inferno on Facebook&lt;/a&gt; (has some more pictures of the band, but not very good ones)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://soundcloud.com/lightbulb-inferno/&#34;&gt;Lightbulb Inferno on Soundcloud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.myspace.com/lightbulbinferno&#34;&gt;Lightbulb Inferno on Myspace (I know..)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
[1] Hence the need I had to find &lt;a href=&#34;http://dieter.plaetinck.be/handing_off_uzbl_to_a_new_project_leader.html&#34;&gt;a new maintainer for Uzbl&lt;/a&gt;)
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Muse ... wow</title>
      <link>http://dieter.plaetinck.be/post/muse...wow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2008 10:33:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>53 at http://dieter.plaetinck.be</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Weird as it might sound, I&#39;ve never bothered to listen to Muse songs.. until now.  Some people have recommended the band to me so I really had to stop ignoring this band someday.  And wow.. what have I been missing al that time :/&lt;br /&gt;
Songs like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VTd6nyHuPdw&#34;&gt;Butterflies and Hurricanes&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=W4R84e1HqvU&#34;&gt;Citizen Erased&lt;/a&gt; are among the most beautiful songs I&#39;ve ever heard now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The key to mastering a musical instrument ...</title>
      <link>http://dieter.plaetinck.be/post/the_key_to_mastering_a_musical_instrument/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2008 23:36:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>35 at http://dieter.plaetinck.be</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The key to mastering a musical instrument is learning an other.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The perfect GTK music player: can Exaile replace Amarok?</title>
      <link>http://dieter.plaetinck.be/post/the_perfect_gtk_music_player_can_exaile_replace_amarok/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2007 12:50:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>25 at http://dieter.plaetinck.be</guid>
      <description>&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Requirements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First a list of features I would like to see in my new music player.  Let&#39;s keep it real: I don&#39;t think there is &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; music player out there that does everything listed here, not even Amarok.  I can live with some missing features, as long as it has the most important ones.  The other features might be added later on anyway, and who knows, maybe I&#39;ll start contributing to a project if I really like it...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order of importance:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Last.fm submitting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jack output&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advanced management of songs/albums/artists and playlists with ratings (not just bookmarks)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Last.fm stream listening&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ipod support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Radio streams&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Podcasts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Artist/album/song information fetching from Wikipedia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;File system monitoring (Inotify) so that it detects the new songs when I add them to my file system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lyrics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Volume normalization (either through &lt;a href=&#34;http://replaygain.hydrogenaudio.org/&#34;&gt;ReplayGain&lt;/a&gt; or just automatically) (if this is not built-in I can always route through a compressor/limiter myself)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stuff that other people like, but I don&#39;t need/want/care about:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On screen display (when a new song starts)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visualizations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Musicbrainz(*)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CD-ripping (not the task of a music player imho)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(*): I absolutely love Musicbrainz and use it all the time but I don&#39;t think it is functionality to be put in a music player.  I use the Musicbrainz Picard tagger to organize my collection.  Putting all the needed functionality inside the media player would make it very bloated.  So in theory I actually wouldn&#39;t need any tag editing at all in my music player&lt;br /&gt;
(this could be a discussion in it&#39;s own merit: why don&#39;t we get rid of all tag editing functionality in all music players and use decent, separate utilities such as the Musicbrainz Picard tagger to tag your collection?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Contenders&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It struck me how many GTK music players there are out there, and especially how similar some of them are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sacredchao.net/quodlibet/&#34;&gt;Quod Libet&lt;/a&gt;: written in python, pretty advanced (podcasts, shoutcasts, Last.fm submissions, reg-exp song searching)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.musicpd.org&#34;&gt;mpd&lt;/a&gt;: although I like a daemon based approach (I sometimes don&#39;t have X open - pretty seldomly though - ) it (even combined with any of the graphical front ends) doesn&#39;t offer anything close to my requirements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://banshee-project.org&#34;&gt;Banshee&lt;/a&gt;: built on Mono. Has podcasts, ipod support, smart playlists, and even inotify support but didn&#39;t even compile on Gentoo, so never mind...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.listen-project.org/&#34;&gt;Listen&lt;/a&gt;: written in python, it looks pretty advanced: podcasts, shoutcasts, Last.fm, Wikipedia fetching, ... it can even create playlists for you based on your Last.fm account&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://live.gnome.org/Rhythmbox&#34;&gt;Rhythmbox&lt;/a&gt;: Gnomes music player inspired by Apple&#39;s iTunes.  featuring internet radio, ratings, lyrics, artwork, Last.fm, podcasts, cd-ripping, ipod writing (only partial !), plugins, file system monitoring (I think through polling, not through inotify).  According to some people it&#39;s pretty buggy and I can only agree: version 0.10 (latest)  crashed many times on me :(&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.exaile.org&#34;&gt;Exaile&lt;/a&gt; I kept the best one for the end ;-).  It&#39;s another one written in python, inspired by Amarok and hence has many similar features.  In addition to that you can also get guitar tabs with it. (why no drum tabs? ;-) ) According to somebody on trac it&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://exaile.org/trac/ticket/485&#34;&gt;better then Listen&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;is Exaile a worthy alternative?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Description on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.exaile.org/&#34;&gt;Exaile website&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;cite&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Exaile is a music player aiming to be similar to KDE&#39;s Amarok, but for GTK+ and written in Python. It incorporates many of the cool things from Amarok (and other media players) like automatic fetching of album art, handling of large libraries, lyrics fetching, artist/album information via Wikipedia, Last.fm submission support, and optional iPod support via a plugin.&lt;br /&gt;
In addition, Exaile also includes a built-in SHOUTcast directory browser, tabbed playlists (so you can have more than one playlist open at a time), blacklisting of tracks (so they don&#39;t get scanned into your library), downloading of guitar tablature from fretplay.com, and submitting played tracks on your iPod to Last.fm&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The description pretty much sums up all there is about Exaile.&lt;br /&gt;
However I want to add it also supports podcasts and streaming radio.&lt;br /&gt;
You can also rate all your tracks and it has some smart playlists (depending on ratings, newest, random, top tracks, ...)&lt;br /&gt;
It uses sqlite (no MySql support like Amarok, which is not a big miss)&lt;br /&gt;
The fact that it allows to have multiple playlists / radio&#39;s / ... open in tabs is a killer feature! (Amarok guys: implement this too!)&lt;br /&gt;
Another cool thing are the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.exaile.org/plugs&#34;&gt;plugins&lt;/a&gt; which add even more functionality, and it&#39;s very easy to install them from inside the program, enabling goes instantly (without the need of a restart)&lt;br /&gt;
Also, it can output via jack, because it uses the GStreamer framework.  It does however create a new jack instance for each song, so each time a song changes, it drops the current jack output and creates a new one.  I don&#39;t like this, because each time have to re-attach my routings, maybe there is some automated way to do this (with &lt;a href=&#34;http://qjackctl.sourceforge.net/&#34;&gt;qjackctl&lt;/a&gt; or something?) but I haven&#39;t figured it out yet.  If anyone knows more about this, let me know!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When last.fm submission fails (eg when your connection is down) it doesn&#39;t keep a queue to resend later like Amarok does, also it currently doesn&#39;t offer Last.fm radio streaming.&lt;br /&gt;
When searching through your collection the results aren&#39;t updated instantly: it takes a second or so (just like when using Amarok, so that&#39;s fine)&lt;br /&gt;
I don&#39;t think Exaile can automatically mount your Ipod for you.  But I don&#39;t think this is the task of the media player:  You can always use a deamon (or your DE) to do that (I use thunar-volman in Xfce for that).  The media player should however work well with the device, after it&#39;s mounted.  In Exaile the Ipod plugin works pretty well, when you mount your Ipod you can make it connect to it, show you the playlists and songs, and you can add songs and playlists just like in Amarok.  I couldn&#39;t, however, edit the playlist that was on the Ipod and creating and deleting a new playlist was a bit buggy (gui still showing old entry with some random ascii characters instead of not showing the playlist anymore)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a last negative point, it seems to not support inotify as of yet.  You can configure it to systematically re-scan your collection every specific interval which is okay, but doesn&#39;t come close to inotify (especially for huge collections)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, to conclude I would say Exaile is a worthy alternative for Amarok, which is a huge thing to say.  It doesn&#39;t offer everything Amarok does, but it does have most important features and even offers some - useful ones - that Amarok doesn&#39;t have.  And I never had it to crash or anything like that, it behaved well and stable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project is however pretty young and it is being actively developed.  Which is a must because some features still need to be implemented (such as inotify support and Last.fm streaming)&lt;br /&gt;
But I see much activity on trac, especially in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.exaile.org/trac/tags/&#39;last.fm&#39;&#34;&gt;the domain of Last.fm&lt;/a&gt; where I can see that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.exaile.org/trac/ticket/299&#34;&gt;support for Last.fm streams is scheduled for the next minor release (0.2.11)&lt;/a&gt; so I&#39;m not worrying and I&#39;m using Exaile full time right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven&#39;t deleted Amarok just yet, but I don&#39;t think that will take very long ;-) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&#39;t take my word for it, but if I ever find the time for it,  I would even like to get intimate with the code base and do some contributions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
