<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>linux on Dieter&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in linux on Dieter&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2012 23:05:05 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lighttpd socket Arch Linux /var/run tmpfs tmpfiles.d</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/lighttpd-socket-arch-linux-var-run-tmpfs-tmpfiles.d/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2012 23:05:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/lighttpd-socket-arch-linux-var-run-tmpfs-tmpfiles.d/</guid>
      
      <description>On Arch Linux, and probably many other distros /run is a new tmpfs, and /var/run symlinks to it. With Lighttpd you might have a fastcgi socket defined something like &#34;/var/run/lighttpd/sockets/mywebsite.sock&#34;. This won&#39;t work anymore as after each reboot /var/run is an empty directory and lighttpd won&#39;t start, /var/log/lighttpd/error.log will tell you: 2012-03-16 09:21:34: (log.c.166) server started 2012-03-16 09:21:34: (mod_fastcgi.c.977) bind failed for: unix:/var/run/lighttpd/sockets/mywebsite.sock-0 No such file or directory 2012-03-16 09:21:34: (mod_fastcgi.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where are the new Arch Linux release images?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/where_are_the_new_arch_linux_images/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2011 21:29:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/where_are_the_new_arch_linux_images/</guid>
      
      <description></description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Restoring ssh connections on resume</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/restoring_ssh_connections_on_resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2010 18:11:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/restoring_ssh_connections_on_resume/</guid>
      
      <description>I use pm-utils for hibernation support.
It has a hooks system which can execute stuff upon hibernate/suspend/thaw/resume/..., but they run as root.
If you want to run stuff as a regular user you could do something like
su $user -c &amp;lt;command&amp;gt;..but these commands have no access to your user environment.
In my user environment I have a variable which I need access to, namely SSH_AUTH_SOCK, which points to my agent which has some unlocked ssh keys.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ext3 logical partition resizing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ext3_logical_partition_resizing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 10:17:26 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ext3_logical_partition_resizing/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You probably know you can resize primary partitions by deleting them and recreating them, keeping the starting block the same but using a higher block as ending point.  You can then increase the filesystem.&lt;br /&gt;
But what about logical partitions?  A while back I had to resize an ext3 logical partition which ended at the end of the last logical partition.  I learned some usefull stuff but I only made some quick scratch notes and I don&#39;t remember all details so:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Do not expect a nice tutorial here, it&#39;s more of a commented dump of my scratch notes and some vague memories.&lt;br /&gt;
The information in this post is not 100% accurate&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I wondered if I could just drop and recreate the extended partition (and if needed, recreating all contained logical partitions, the last one being bigger of course) but nowhere I could find information about that.&lt;br /&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Opening files automatically on mainstream Linux desktops</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/opening_files_automatically_on_mainstream_linux_desktops/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2009 19:43:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/opening_files_automatically_on_mainstream_linux_desktops/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Xfce/Gnu/Linux works amazingly well on my moms workstation, with one exception: opening files automatically with the correct program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two biggest culprits are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gtk&#39;s &#34;open file with&#34; dialog: if any Gtk program doesn&#39;t know how to open a file it brings up this dialog that is horrible to use.  You can search through your entire VFS for the right executable.  No thumbnails, no usage of .desktop files, $PATH, autocompletion and not even limiting the scope to directories such as /usr/bin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mozilla software such as Firefox and Thunderbird: they only seem to differentiate files by their mimetype, not by extension.  There are add-ons to make it easier to edit these preferences, but eventually you&#39;re in a dead end because you get files with correct extensions but unuseful mimetimes (application/octet-stream)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily the fd.o guys have come up with &lt;a href=&#34;http://standards.freedesktop.org/desktop-entry-spec/desktop-entry-spec-latest.html&#34;&gt;.desktop files&lt;/a&gt;.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jobhunt over.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/jobhunt_over/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2008 18:07:35 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/jobhunt_over/</guid>
      
      <description>What better way to launch the new year then starting to work as a System Engineer/Developer for a consulting firm where everyone breathes Linux and Open Source?
Next week I&#39;ll start at Kangaroot. Woohoo.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking for a new job</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/looking_for_a_new_job/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2008 20:30:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/looking_for_a_new_job/</guid>
      
      <description>The adventure at Netlog didn&#39;t work out entirely, so I&#39;m looking for a new challenge!
My new ideal (slightly utopic) job would be:
Conceptual engineering while still being close to the technical side as well, most notably system engineering and development. Innovative: go where no one has gone before. Integrated in the open-source world. (Bonus points for companies where open source is key in their business model) To get a detailed overview of my interests and skills, I refer to:</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AIF: the brand new Arch Linux Installation Framework</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/aif_the_brand_new_arch_linux_installation_framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2008 11:45:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/aif_the_brand_new_arch_linux_installation_framework/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I started thinking about writing my own automatic installer that would set up my system exactly the way I want.&lt;br /&gt;
(See &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/rethinking_the_backup_paradigm_a_higher-level_approach&#34; title=&#34;/rethinking_the_backup_paradigm_a_higher-level_approach&#34;&gt;rethinking_the_backup_paradigm_a_higher-level...&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I looked at the official Arch install scripts to see if I could reuse parts of their code, but unfortunately the code was just one big chunk of bash code with the main program and &#34;flow control&#34; (you must first do this step, then that), UI-code (dialogs etc) and backend logic (create filesystems, ...) all mangled up and mixed very closely together.&lt;br /&gt;
Functionality-wise the installer works fine, but I guess the code behind it is the result of years of adding features and quick fixes without refactoring, making it impossible to reuse any of the code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I started to write &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/Dieterbe/aif/&#34;&gt;AIF: the Arch Linux Installation Framework&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m done with Gnome/Gconf</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/im_done_with_gnome_and_gconf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2008 22:01:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/im_done_with_gnome_and_gconf/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m managing my ~ in svn but using gnome &amp;amp; gconf makes this rather hard.&lt;br /&gt;
They mangle cache data together with user data and user preferences and spread that mix over several directories in your home  (.gconf, .gnome2 etc).&lt;br /&gt;
The .gconf directory is the worst.  This is where many applications store all their stuff.   User preferences but also various %gconf.xml files, which seem to be updated automatically everytime &#39;something&#39; happens:  They keep track of timestamps for various events such as when you press numlock or become available on pidgin.&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m fine with the fact they do that.  I&#39;m sure it enables them to provide some additional functionality.  But they need to do it in clearly separated places (such as &lt;a href=&#34;http://standards.freedesktop.org/basedir-spec/basedir-spec-0.6.html&#34;&gt;xdg&#39;s&lt;/a&gt; $XDG_CACHE_HOME directory)</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking the backup paradigm: a higher-level approach</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/rethinking_the_backup_paradigm_a_higher-level_approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2008 20:21:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/rethinking_the_backup_paradigm_a_higher-level_approach/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this post I explain my vision on the concepts of backups and how several common practices are in my opinion suboptimal and become unnecessary or at least can be done more easily by managing data on a higher level by employing other patterns such as versioning important directories and distributed data management.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the Netlog Developer Pages</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/announcing_the_netlog_developer_pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2008 12:39:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/announcing_the_netlog_developer_pages/</guid>
      
      <description>At work, we&#39;ve setup the Netlog Developer Pages
It is the place where you can/will find all information around our OpenSocial implementation, our own API, skin development, sample code and so on.
We&#39;ve also launched a group where you can communicate with fellow developers and Netlog employees.
The page also features a blog where you can follow what is going on in the Netlog Tech team.
PS: We&#39;ve also updated our jobs page</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple command to retrieve stuff from RAM after closing/crashing an application</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/simple_command_to_retrieve_stuff_from_ram_after_closing_or_crashing_an_application/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2007 15:32:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/simple_command_to_retrieve_stuff_from_ram_after_closing_or_crashing_an_application/</guid>
      
      <description>After an app is closed or crashed, the data is still in your RAM and you can very easily get it back by grepping /proc/kcore.
thanks Martin for this tip!
http://www.matusiak.eu/numerodix/blog/index.php/2007/09/10/recover-lost-...</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assymetric keys instead of passwords for SSH authentication to increase security and convenience</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/assymetric_keys_instead_of_passwords_for_ssh_authentication_to_increase_security_and_convenience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2007 20:22:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/assymetric_keys_instead_of_passwords_for_ssh_authentication_to_increase_security_and_convenience/</guid>
      
      <description>I&#39;ve been using OpenSSH already for a while and although I&#39;ve seen mentions of &#34;public key authentication&#34; and &#34;RSA encryption&#34; several times in it&#39;s config files, I never decided to figure out what it did exactly, and stuck to password authentication. But now the guys at work explained how it works and after reading more about it, I&#39;m totally hooked on it!
It&#39;s a feature in ssh protocol version 2 (thus it&#39;s around for already a while, e.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The perfect GTK music player: can Exaile replace Amarok?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the_perfect_gtk_music_player_can_exaile_replace_amarok/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2007 12:50:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the_perfect_gtk_music_player_can_exaile_replace_amarok/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve always liked Amarok: it does everything I always wanted, &lt;em&gt; and more&lt;/em&gt;.  It looks perfect in every way ...&lt;br /&gt;
But .. it uses the QT library, and although there are tricks to make QT applications more fit in with your gtk desktop/theme it will never fit in perfectly, not only graphically but also because you still need to load the qt libraries when you want to listen to some music and it is built to interact with the KDE desktop environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I&#39;ve been looking for an alternative, a GTK application strong enough to actually be able to replace Amarok, the king of all software music players.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open source en softwarepatenten vanuit een ethisch perspectief</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/open_source_softwarepatenten_vanuit_ethisch_perspectief/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2007 00:53:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/open_source_softwarepatenten_vanuit_ethisch_perspectief/</guid>
      
      <description>Voor school moest ik een ethisch verslag schrijven.
Hier moesten 3 elementen in voorkomen:
Inleidende tekst / Persoonlijke reflectie over beroeps- en bedrijfsethiek Ethische beschouwingen bij het eindwerk Uitgebreidere verhandeling met ethische beschouwingen over een vraagstuk naar keuze uit het domein van wetenschap, techniek, beroeps- en bedrijfsleven. In mijn geval is dit vraagstuk naar keuze &#34;open source en softwarepatenten&#34; geworden Zoals sommigen onder jullie weten vind ik ethiek een heel belangrijk aspect in het leven en ik ben dan ook blij dat ik het issue van open source en softwarepatenten verder heb kunnen uitdiepen, want dit is iets waar ik in geinteresseerd ben.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I just became a &#34;System &amp; Network Architect&#34;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/i_just_became_a_system_and_network_architect/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2007 20:11:07 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/i_just_became_a_system_and_network_architect/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just signed my contract at &lt;a href=&#34;http://incrowd.be/&#34;&gt;Incrowd&lt;/a&gt;, the company behind sites such as &lt;a href=&#34;http://redbox.be/&#34;&gt;redbox&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebox.com/&#34;&gt;facebox&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will be working there in a team of all young, enthusiastic people.  Among those, some people are already familiar to me:  my old friend &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lievendekeyser.net/&#34;&gt;Lieven&lt;/a&gt; (we&#39;ve played in a band together but kept in touch afterwards) and my ex-classmate &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jurriaanpersyn.com/&#34;&gt;Jurriaan&lt;/a&gt;.  Both of them love their jobs btw :-).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My official title is &#34;System &amp;amp; Network architect&#34;.&lt;br /&gt;
Things I will be doing there is </description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debian changing route: the end of the perfect server linux distribution?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/debian_changing_route_the_end_of_the_perfect_server_distribution/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2007 11:58:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/debian_changing_route_the_end_of_the_perfect_server_distribution/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From the very little experience I have with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.debian.org/&#34;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt;, and from the stuff I&#39;ve been reading about it, I think I can safely say Debian has always been a special distribution: packages always take very long to get into the stable tree, because Debian wanted to be a rock solid system where packages go through a lot of testing.  (&#34;We release it when it&#39;s done&#34;)  The end result is a distro where you don&#39;t have the latest software, neither as much flexibility as, say &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gentoo.org/&#34;&gt;Gentoo&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.archlinux.org&#34;&gt;Arch&lt;/a&gt;: You&#39;d many times need to adapt your way of doing things to the &#34;Debian way&#34; (or be prepared to look for help in really obscure places and probably break things) but the end result is a stable distro where everything works very decently.  That, combined with no licensing fees (unlike for example &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.redhat.com&#34;&gt;Red hat&lt;/a&gt;), make it the perfect choice for a server in small companies, where money is more important then features such as professional support or official certifications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, it seems like Debian is taking a route that will make it lose it&#39;s advantages over other distributions in the server market:</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fosdem 2007 review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/fosdem_2007_review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2007 21:02:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/fosdem_2007_review/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every year, during a special weekend in February, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ulb.ac.be/&#34;&gt;University Libre of Brussels&lt;/a&gt; suddenly becomes a little more geeky.&lt;br /&gt;
It&#39;s that time of the year when many European (and some inter-continental) colleagues join us at&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fosdem.org&#34;&gt;Fosdem: the Free and Open source Software Developers&#39; European Meeting&lt;/a&gt; (more info &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fosdem.org/about/fosdem&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My favorite bash tricks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my_favorite_bash_tricks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2007 23:38:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my_favorite_bash_tricks/</guid>
      
      <description>Hello everyone.
This post is about bash, the shell providing so many users easy access to the underlying power of their system.
(not bash the quote database, although i really like that website too ;-) )
Most people know the basics, but getting to know it better can really increase your productivity. And when that happens, you might start loving bash as much as I do ;-)
I assume you have a basic knowledge of bash, the history mechanism, and ~/.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello world!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/blogpost1_hello_world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2007 14:45:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/blogpost1_hello_world/</guid>
      
      <description>Finally, my own website...
I already wanted to get this up for a long time. My initial idea was writing (and styling) it all from scratch using the marvelous CakePHP framework along with an authentication system i wrote, dAuth.
However, due to my lack of time I decided to use the excellent drupal platform, of which I&#39;m quite sure will get the job done equally well, while drastically liberating my time, so I can invest it in other projects :-)</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
