<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Life on Dieter Plaetinck&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life on Dieter Plaetinck&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2012 16:50:11 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving to New York City</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/moving-to-nyc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2012 16:50:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/moving-to-nyc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have a one-way ticket to NYC on Sept. 21st.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/about&#34;&gt;Vimeo HQ&lt;/a&gt; is in Manhattan, and practically the whole team works in the building so it makes sense for me to relocate and join them locally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to working with the colleagues face to face, but mainly I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to the experience of living in such a different place, and exploring the US.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, I already have some small trips planned (Hamptons NY, camping in Pennsylvania, skiing in New York this winter) with some friends &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/thailand_berlin_velocity_nyc_ghent_metal.html&#34;&gt;I met last year in NY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re also looking into possibly going to California or Mexico for the holidays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been living in &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ghent&#34;&gt;Ghent&lt;/a&gt; for about a year now and absolutely loved it.  I&amp;rsquo;ll definitely miss Ghent, I think NYC might be a bit too hectic for my taste, but I just &lt;i&gt;have&lt;/i&gt; to try this and see :)  There&amp;rsquo;s so much to learn and explore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I especially have high expectations of the music scene, which I&amp;rsquo;ld like to get involved in. (btw my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lightbulbinferno.com/&#34;&gt;ex-band&lt;/a&gt; is recording an EP and looking for a new drummer)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;35%&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/files/travel_documents_nyc.jpg&#34;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

As for things in Belgium: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.10151066748715279.458359.627030278&amp;type=3&amp;l=1fa8adec26&#34;&gt;selling furniture&lt;/a&gt;, moving out of my apartment next weekend, having a goodbye drink friday sept. 14th, flying a week later and returning in the summer 2013 for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gentsefeesten.be/&#34;&gt;gentse feesten&lt;/a&gt;.  Maybe I&#39;ll visit sooner, depending on how homesick I get :)

&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thailand, Berlin Velocity EU, NYC, Ghent and more metal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/thailand_berlin_velocity_nyc_ghent_metal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2012 18:10:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/thailand_berlin_velocity_nyc_ghent_metal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt;Thailand&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In July I did a 3-week group journey through Thailand arranged by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.explorado.be&#34;&gt;Explorado&lt;/a&gt;, but organized by (&amp;ldquo;outsourced to&amp;rdquo;) the 2 guides of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rootsofasia.com/&#34;&gt;roots of Asia&lt;/a&gt;, who did &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rootsofasia.com/get-to-know-us/feedback.html&#34;&gt;an amazing job&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whole concept was exploring &amp;ldquo;the real Thailand&amp;rdquo; by means of &lt;i&gt;Eco-tourism&lt;/i&gt;.  We&amp;rsquo;ve been in Bangkok (twice), Chiang Mai city, a mountain village in the province of Chiang Mai, through the jungle, at a fisherman village in Phuket and at the tropical island of Koh Pha ngan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latter was at the end of the trip and was timed perfectly to get some deserved rest in a more touristy (although not too busy) area, but the majority of the trip was spent far away from the typical touristy areas so we could be submerged in honest, authentic Thai culture and visit authentic locations, often we were at locations where seeing a group of white folks is not common.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve been at unique authentic temples, stayed with various locals and hill tribes, shared meals with them, took the same transport they did (at one point an entire village collected their bikes so we could borrow them to do a bike trip through rice fields and some of the most beautiful lakes I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen).  We&amp;rsquo;ve had plenty of beautiful moments during those 3 weeks.  Like visiting the home of one of the local Thai who built his entire house out of clay, by himself and some friends, or visiting the ancient temple where our guide got married, in a forest in the hills, it was the most beautiful temple of the entire trip, but no other tourists go there because it&amp;rsquo;s not really known (and should probably be kept that way).  Or going to a bar in Chiang Mai city (one evening on my own, the next I brought a fellow traveler) to have some good times with some locals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Eco-conscious part of the travel means:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;

&lt;li&gt;green travel (minimize impact on the environment, &#34;leave no trace&#34;).  Other than taking the plane over there and back we did a pretty good job, we&#39;ve used public buses, night trains, biodegradable soap, etc&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;local foods (no import, minimal packaging, wrap in banana leaves, etc)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;supporting Eco-conscious projects (like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.elephantnaturepark.org/&#34;&gt;elephant nature park&lt;/a&gt;, which is an entire volunteer-based reserve to give mistreated elephants (which has been a big problem in Thailand) a better life, where we washed and fed elephants)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has been a great experience, and although I found the culture in the South disgustingly based on profiting from tourists, and the cities are too polluted and dirty, I&amp;rsquo;ve seen cultures so respectful of nature and each other, living by values I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to apply at home - but being frowned upon in our western society because we&amp;rsquo;re so brainwashed by consumerism, which was beautiful and heartwarming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/files/thailand_jungle.jpg&#34; height=&#34;150px&#34;/&gt; --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/files/thailand_elephant.jpg&#34; height=&#34;150px&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/files/thailand_tree.jpg&#34; height=&#34;150px&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/files/thailand_tribe.jpg&#34; height=&#34;150px&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/files/thailand_gekko.jpg&#34; height=&#34;150px&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/files/thailand_boat.jpg&#34; height=&#34;150px&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/files/thailand_emblem.jpg&#34; height=&#34;150px&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/files/thailand_hangmat.jpg&#34; height=&#34;150px&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.10150511397165279.397476.627030278&amp;type=1&amp;l=2e7844ab2b&#34;&gt;Photo album&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Berlin&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;float:left;margin:0 5px 0 0;&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/files/berlin_velocity.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Berlin Velocity EU conference&#34; height=&#34;150px&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;float:left;margin:0 5px 0 0;&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/files/berlin_reichstag.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Berlin Reichstag building&#34; height=&#34;150px&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been in Berlin for the first &lt;a href=&#34;http://velocityconf.com/velocityeu/&#34;&gt;Velocity conference in the EU&lt;/a&gt;, which was quite good.  The best part was probably the &amp;ldquo;Velocity Birds of feather&amp;rdquo; (whatever that means) unconference the day before at &lt;a href=&#34;http://betahaus.de&#34;&gt;betahaus&lt;/a&gt;, which was great for meeting some folks such as the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.soundcloud.com&#34;&gt;soundcloud.com&lt;/a&gt; guys (which BTW, is the site we host our music on), although lots more interesting folks attended the conference itself (and it was packed).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Berlin itself was nice too.  Lots of history (Berlin wall, world war(s)), lots of impressive architecture (old and new), very cheap (albeit mediocre in quality) food, lots of Italian food, a bit cold though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 style=&#34;clear: left;&#34;&gt;New York city&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;float:left;margin:0 5px 0 0;&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/files/brooklyn_bridge.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Brooklyn bridge&#34; height=&#34;150px&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;float:left;margin:0 5px 0 0;&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/files/manhattan_harbor.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Manhattan harbor&#34; height=&#34;150px&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still recovering from the awesome time I just had in NYC. I&amp;rsquo;ve been way more busy over there than I anticipated. I should have stayed 2 or 3 weeks instead of 1 :).  I&amp;rsquo;ve met various locals (one of whom who&amp;rsquo;d love to become a city guide as 2nd job because she just loves showing people around, so that just turned out great!). I didn&amp;rsquo;t go for the typical touristy things (I skipped things like the WTC memorial, empire state building, statue of liberty, to the extent you can skip them, as they are very visible from pretty much all over the place).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, I wanted to get a feel of the real city and the people inhabiting it.  I&amp;rsquo;ve seen parts of Queens, central and North-West Brooklyn, lots of areas (but not enough) in Manhattan and even Staten Island, been to a rock concert, comedy, improv and cabaret shows, the movies, more bars than I can count and mostly ate out with company (just as real new yorkers do, of course, though for breakfast that feels a bit weird).  I even went shopping (not mall-shopping, but groceries in the supermarket, the Williamsburg Foodtown - that&amp;rsquo;s what it&amp;rsquo;s called - clerk advised me to enjoy every last second in the US, phrased in a way as if any other place in the world sucks in comparison, which is ridiculous, but turns out I followed his advice anyway) because I stayed at an apartment in Williamsburg, I also had 2 roommates, with whom I ironically couldn&amp;rsquo;t spend as much time as I wanted to as I was so busy meeting up with all those other people, I also visited the Etsy and Vimeo offices (both are awesome) and met up with Dave Reisner (who is one of our latest Arch Linux devs, and who lives in NJ, but don&amp;rsquo;t tell anyone) and who forgot to show me around in the Google office ;-)  And I realize some of the past sentences are a bit long and busy but that&amp;rsquo;s one of the things I learned at New York I guess.  For one week, I almost lived like a real New Yorker, and it was interesting (but exhausting).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 style=&#34;clear: left;&#34;&gt;Move to Ghent&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;float:left;margin:0 5px 0 0;&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/files/ghent_bridge.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Ghent, bridge of Sint-Michiels&#34; height=&#34;150px&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;float:left;margin:0 5px 0 0;&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/files/ghent_coupure.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Ghent, coupure&#34; height=&#34;150px&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enough about the trips.  Back to daily life.  I moved to the city of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ghent&#34;&gt;Ghent&lt;/a&gt;.  Riding by bike to work every day along the scenic &lt;a href=&#34;http://nl.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coupure_%28Gent%29&#34;&gt;Coupure&lt;/a&gt; is fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am quite proud to say nearly all of my stuff in this apartment is second hand and I&amp;rsquo;ve been lucky to receive some free stuff as well (thanks Bram!).  Not (only) because I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration:line-through&#34;&gt;cheap&lt;/span&gt; money conscious but I like to give things a second life instead of buying something new, lowering the impact on the environment. Even if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t look too well, as long as it&amp;rsquo;s functional.  And this is exactly one of those values I mentioned above which is often not understood in our Western society but I was pleased to find out this philosophy is the standard in large parts of Thai culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 style=&#34;clear: left;&#34;&gt;Death metal&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;float:left;margin:0 5px 0 0;&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/files/li_promoshoot.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Promo shoot&#34; height=&#34;150px&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;float:left;margin:0 5px 0 0;&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/files/li_frontline.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Live @ Frontline, Ghent&#34; height=&#34;150px&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve done 3 gigs (which had great reception, luckily) and we&amp;rsquo;ve got planned a few already for 2012, one of which will be at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/pages/From-Rock-Till-Core/141364465969247&#34;&gt;From Rock Till Core festival&lt;/a&gt; in Merelbeke.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also did a semi-professional &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lightbulbinferno.com/album_promoshoot_summer_2011&#34;&gt;photo-shoot&lt;/a&gt;, and I made a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lightbulbinferno.com/&#34;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; (you can tell I&amp;rsquo;m not a designer).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br style=&#34;clear: left;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That wraps up 2011 for me. Good times.. Happy new year everybody!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hitchhiking.. try it.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/hitchhiking_try_it/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2011 16:04:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/hitchhiking_try_it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;travel between home and work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What started as a &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure about this, it seems a bit awkward, but I do&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;want to know how it goes and feels, so I&amp;rsquo;ll try it out once&amp;rdquo; ended up being &amp;ldquo;this is&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;great, I&amp;rsquo;m doing it every day and loving it&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s why you should try it and why it may make your life more awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Why do I do it?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Meet new interesting people.  I meet a lot of different people with all kinds of

  backgrounds.  Male, female.  Young, old.  Native Belgians, immigrants,

students, anything from &#34;lower class&#34; people, to people with regular jobs to even some people with very exciting

lives and/or high profile jobs.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;It&#39;s better for the planet.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Save time and/or money.  For me, traveling to/from work by hitchhiking is

  quicker than going by public transport (bus).  Bonus points because my route

involves a pleasant bike ride to the highway entry where I start my little

adventure.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;No concerns about parking and/or paying for gas.  My job is near the

  highway exit so usually I get dropped off literally in front of the building.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Why do people take you with them?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From what I can tell:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;

&lt;li&gt;They like to do something nice, it makes them feel like a better person

  (rightly so).&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;They are bored in the car and would like some companionship.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Out of compassion.  &#34;poor guy must be standing here for a long time&#34;,

  which is rarely true, and I think compassion is not needed, but hey.

  Some drivers told me &#34;I did the same when I was a student so I know it feels

  like&#34;.  Most folks are surprised though when I tell them I do it because I

like to.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Concern that something bad will happen to you. Which I also think is not

  really needed, but hey.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;curiosity, they want to hear your story.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Why you should try it&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I learned is, not only can hitchhiking bring you to work faster than by&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;public transport and/or in a less polluting manner, it can be a fun experience for both you and person&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;picking you up.  Indeed, some people that pick me up never picked anybody up before&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and tell me at the end they were happy they did it, and you can tell their day is made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, avoiding routine makes your days more memorable and interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Btw, I recently stumbled on &amp;lt;a&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;href=&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://lifehacker.com/5800954/escape-the-rut-of-your-daily-routine-by-trying-something-new-for-30-days&amp;quot;&amp;gt;this&#34;&gt;http://lifehacker.com/5800954/escape-the-rut-of-your-daily-routine-by-trying-something-new-for-30-days&amp;quot;&amp;gt;this&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;presentation&lt;/a&gt;, which tells you how you can make your daily life more&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;interesting and memorable by trying out new things, the video fits this post&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;well :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Tips&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Sometimes you can have bad luck (no pick up, traffic jam, ...).  It helps if

  you have flexible working hours like me.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Have some good card boards with your destination clearly written.  If you live in a small

  village like me, write down the name of a bigger city which is in the same

direction.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Find a spot where drivers have time to see you, have some time to read your

  cardboard and to make up their mind about whether or not to pick you up and then have enough room

to legally put their car to allow you to get in.  All this without endangering

other people in traffic.  When going to work I can stand just at the entry to the highway,

where not that many cars pass, but I have an almost guaranteed pickup within 5

minutes because drivers have time to react.  Whereas when going from work back home, I have no choice but to stand

at a very busy section where drivers have little time to react (avg pickup time there

is 10 minutes or a bit more).&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;look decently dressed. People tell me they felt okay picking me up

  because I look civilized.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;If you&#39;re a girl, it could be trickier because you could feel uncomfortable

  with some people who pick you up.  That said, I think there are many more people with good

intentions then bad, and you can always say &#34;no thanks&#34; and wait for the next

ride.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: this article is not accurate anymore.  I have since moved to Ghent, where&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I go to work by bike, but that&amp;rsquo;s material for a future post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My metal band</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/my_metalband/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2011 14:58:12 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/my_metalband/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since the audience of this blog is largely technical, I don&#39;t post much about other topics, but I feel it&#39;s time for a short summary about one of my &#34;real life projects&#34;.

&lt;br/&gt;In the spring of 2009 I joined a progressive death metal band.  I&#39;ve been drumming since I was 17, but during the last 2 years I&#39;ve been practising and rehearsing like never before.[1]

&lt;br/&gt;When you hear yourself on tape for the first time, it&#39;s a bit of disillusionment as you suddenly hear every imperfection, many of which you didn&#39;t realise you had (or didn&#39;t think were very noticeable).

&lt;br/&gt;So 2 years of practicing, rehearsing, test recordings, real recordings, mixing sessions (where you really grow a good ear towards imperfections) later we are now getting to the point where we can nail our stuff and are looking very forward to our first gig, which will be June 3rd in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jhsjatoo.org/&#34;&gt;jh sjatoo&lt;/a&gt; in Kalken.

We&#39;ve written about 7 songs, of which at this point we play 5. I wish we had proper recordings of all of them, but &#34;Total Annihilation&#34; captures several aspects of our style:

&lt;object height=&#34;225&#34; width=&#34;65%&#34;&gt; &lt;param name=&#34;movie&#34; value=&#34;http://player.soundcloud.com/player.swf?url=http%3A%2F%2Fapi.soundcloud.com%2Fusers%2F2762471&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name=&#34;allowscriptaccess&#34; value=&#34;always&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;embed allowscriptaccess=&#34;always&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; src=&#34;http://player.soundcloud.com/player.swf?url=http%3A%2F%2Fapi.soundcloud.com%2Fusers%2F2762471&#34; type=&#34;application/x-shockwave-flash&#34; width=&#34;65%&#34;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt; &lt;/object&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;In early 2010 I treated myself (found a nice 2nd hand deal) to a new pdp birch kit with Zildjian Z custom cymbals (that was actually at the time I was in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/not_working_for_facebook.html&#34;&gt;interview process for a Palo-Alto position at Facebook&lt;/a&gt; so I might have needed to sell it again soon after, but that didn&#39;t happen).

&lt;br/&gt; Here are some pics:

&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/files/pdp1.jpg&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;,

&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/files/pdp2.jpg&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;,

&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/files/pdp3.jpg&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;,

&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/files/pdp4.jpg&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;.

More info about the band:

&lt;ul&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/lightbulbinferno&#34;&gt;Lightbulb Inferno on Facebook&lt;/a&gt; (has some more pictures of the band, but not very good ones)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://soundcloud.com/lightbulb-inferno/&#34;&gt;Lightbulb Inferno on Soundcloud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.myspace.com/lightbulbinferno&#34;&gt;Lightbulb Inferno on Myspace (I know..)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ul&gt;

[1] Hence the need I had to find &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/handing_off_uzbl_to_a_new_project_leader.html&#34;&gt;a new maintainer for Uzbl&lt;/a&gt;)

&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can we build a simple, cross-distribution installation framework?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/can_we_build_a_simple_cross-distribution_installation_framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2011 23:46:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/can_we_build_a_simple_cross-distribution_installation_framework/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Basically, using the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.archlinux.org/&#34;&gt;Arch&lt;/a&gt; Installation Framework as a starting point, along with the notion that most of the code is actually not Arch-specific I adressed other distros to check&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;if there was any interest in sharing workload on the distribution-agnostic aspects of the framework. If other distros with a similar philosophy of little-abstractions/KISS would join, we would all reap the benefits of a simple, yet quite featureful installer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was some interest, so we&amp;rsquo;ll see what happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/files/lif.pdf&#34;&gt;slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=83xBdlbGHdI&#34;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dir 2011, Fosdem 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/dir_fosdem_2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 23:15:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/dir_fosdem_2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After that, I&amp;rsquo;m going to the devopsdinner and Fosdem beer event in Brussels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On february &lt;sup&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt; of course, Fosdem itself.  Looking forward to the systemd talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On sunday I&amp;rsquo;ll do a talk about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fosdem.org/2011/schedule/event/distro_crossinstall&#34;&gt;simple shell based Gnu/Linux installers&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;like mentioned earlier I hope devs from other &amp;ldquo;lightweight&amp;rdquo;/kiss-style distro&amp;rsquo;s will be present (Gentoo and other *too&amp;rsquo;s, Crux, *ppix, &amp;hellip; You know who you are)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would be interesting to share some common codebase for distribution independent topics (like filesystems), or at least discuss how feasible it would be.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a search engine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/building_a_search_engine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2011 19:15:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/building_a_search_engine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was looking to get back to the challenging world of high-performance and large-scale (web) applications, but I also wanted something more conceptual and researchy, rather then the highly hands-on dev- and ops work I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing for a few years now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://projects.ibbt.be/bom-vl/&#34;&gt;Bom-vl&lt;/a&gt; project is pretty broad: it aims to make the Flemish cultural heritage media more useable by properly digitizing, archiving and making public the (currently mostly analog) archives from providers such as TV stations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/files/blog/ibbt/ilabt2.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, I believe there&#39;s some &gt;100TB of media in our cluster (mostly from VRT, afaik), along with associated textual descriptions/metadata, with more to follow.  The application is currently for a selected audience but the goal is to make it public in the near future.

I&#39;m part of the search engine team, we aim to provide users with the most relevant hits for their queries, by using existing technology (think Lucene, hadoop, etc) or devising our own where needed.

As I&#39;m charged with a similarity search problem (&#34;other videos which might also interest you&#34;), I&#39;m studying information retrieval topics such as index and algorithm design and various vector models. Starting next week, I&#39;ll probably start implementing and testing some approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back from Canada, Archcon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/back_from_canada_archcon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2010 23:10:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/back_from_canada_archcon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt;Archcon&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Archcon was small (20-ish people).  (That&#39;s what you get for doing it in Canada ;), but very nice.&lt;br /&gt;

Interesting talks, informal, good vibe, decent logistics and catering.&lt;br /&gt;

This year it happened because Dusty and Ricardo actually just wanted to have a conference without worrying too much about the attendance,&lt;br /&gt;

next year we should do it again because Arch (conferences) rock(s), and because we need more visitors.  More central locations such as Seattle and Europe have been suggested.&lt;br /&gt;

Either way, next year both Judd (founder) and Aaron (current overlord) should be there. (this year they both had lame excuses like family reunions and &#34;almost getting married&#34;.  Congrats btw, Aaron!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was an absolute pleasure to meet some more of my fellow devs, and users.&lt;br /&gt;

Here is a pic from the group (unfortunately, a few are missing)&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/files/group.jpg&#34;/&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

People in bold are Arch (ex-) devs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Richard (sokuban) from Toronto (linguistics student)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Chris (Gallow) from Toronto&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Alex (alexmat) from Tokyo, Japan (very into NILFS, submitted already some patches)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Sander (GogglesGuy) (Dutch guy living in the states now)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Eric from Seattle, WA&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Gregory (gelendir) from Quebec city, Canada (aka dude wearing the kilt and fivefingers and funny accent)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Kevin (kpiche)&lt;/b&gt; from Ottawa (does perl stuff iirc)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Loui (louipc)&lt;/b&gt; from Toronto, Canada (AUR guy, git lover.  metalfan.  Shook John Petrucci&#39;s hand)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Tim from Annapolis (uses Arch for servers at work with some fancy mass-install scripts)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Dustin (daking) from Stanford, CA (runs most of Stanford university on Arch)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;me&lt;/b&gt; from Belgium (arch-releng/aif, uzbl guy) &lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Walter from Toronto (very into Uzbl, not actually an Arch user... yet)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;David (davekong) from New York City&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Dan (toofishes)&lt;/b&gt; from Chicago (Pacman dev)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Dusty&lt;/b&gt; from Shaunavon SK (shwag, archcon organizer)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Ricardo (ralvez) from  Toronto (archcon organizer)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Jason (Xentac)&lt;/b&gt; from Victoria, BC (entrepeneur, used to use Arch for the business)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;https://bbs.archlinux.org/viewtopic.php?id=101692&#34;&gt;Archcon thread&lt;/a&gt; for more info.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately I barely slept the night before my AIF talk, so I feel that one didn&#39;t go to well.  Although people told me it was OK.&lt;br /&gt;

The Uzbl talk was pretty much what I imagined it to be: like the fosdem talk, but a bit more in depth here and there.&lt;br /&gt;

My pc was behaving weirdly, but luckily I could use Dan&#39;s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ve been lucky that Walter and Isaac had proper, respectively videotaping and photocamera equipment.  So there are plenty of pics, and nearly all talks got videotaped.&lt;br /&gt;

(I think the &#34;hacking pacman&#34; one was the only one not being videotaped, because 2 other talks were going on at the same time.  Too bad, it was a very interesting talk)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://archlinux.ca/archcon2010/images/&#34;&gt;Archcon pictures&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;a href=&#34;http://archlinux.ca/archcon2010/videos/&#34;&gt;Archcon videos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

My slides:&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/files/aif-archcon2010.pdf&#34;&gt;AIF (day 1)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/files/uzbl-archcon2010.pdf&#34;&gt;Uzbl (day 2)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Other days&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some thoughts and notes of what I did and saw around Toronto/Montreal..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;Cities with streets and subways in a grid layout are awesome.  Soo much easier to navigate.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;Red lights with countdown timers (in seconds) are awesome.  Although I&amp;rsquo;m told some places in Europe have them too.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;Toronto was awesome: huge city, many friendly people, low crime rate, many different cultures, very short history.  High park was very nice. &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/files/blog/toronto.ca/high_park_004_500.jpg&#34;/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;Montreal was like a European city: more history, old buildings, more crime, but of course a grid layout.  Some nice views though (ie. from Mont Royal).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;The youth hostels I went too were great: never got to meet so many interesting people in such a short timespan.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;CN tower: I procrastinated visiting until the last day, and when I finally wanted to go in the wheather was perfect, but there was a 2 hour queue, so I skipped it. Anyway there are &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CN_Tower&#34;&gt;plenty of pictures online&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;Niagara falls were beautiful.  Maid of the myst tour was worth it.  I made pictures but &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Niagara_falls_panorama.jpg&#34;&gt;those online&lt;/a&gt; are better.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;I met Kan Johar (founder of &lt;a href=&#34;http://plurk.com&#34;&gt;plurk.com&lt;/a&gt;, amongst others), good times.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;Dusty introduced me to poutine.  I found it disgusting.  I guess you need to be a Canadian before you can like it.&lt;br&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/files/poutine.jpg&#34;/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;Dusty and I have been to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://linuxcaffe.ca/&#34;&gt;Linux Caffe.&lt;/a&gt;  The owner is a great guy, he&amp;rsquo;s considering switching to Arch, and he wrote his whole point of sales, accounting and bookkeeping software using shell scripts, perltk and stuff.  He&amp;rsquo;s into suckless.org stuff.   His version 2.0 will probably be based on Xmonad.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/files/linuxcaffe-pos1.jpg&#34;/&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/files/linuxcaffe-pos2.jpg&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dusty and me, somewhere on our way to the Niagara falls.&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/files/dustyandme.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Off to Toronto July 14-28, Archcon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/off_to_toronto_july_14-28_archcon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2010 11:34:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/off_to_toronto_july_14-28_archcon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a very small conference, and the first of its kind.  At the &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/froscon_2009_afterthoughts&#34;&gt;last FrOSCon&lt;/a&gt; we have been playing with the idea to hold an informal Arch conference in Europe, but those were just ideas.  Dusty and Ricardo beat us with an actual implementation.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is great, and one of the milestones in Arch Linux history.  Which is why I want to be there and help making it better.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.archlinux.ca/archcon2010/?p=116&#34;&gt;Archcon schedule&lt;/a&gt;.  I&#39;ll be talking about AIF and uzbl.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My schedule:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;

&lt;li&gt;wed. July 14: departure&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;July 14 - 21: hanging around in downtown Toronto. Not sure yet where I&#39;ll stay. probably some hostel.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;July 21 - 28: bed and breakfast pretty close to the conference location, outside the city center&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;July 22 - 23 are the conference talks days, July 24-25 are the conference tourist days, where we&#39;ll do some touristy stuff with the conference participants&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;wed. July 28: flying back&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.archlinux.org/index.php/Archcon_extra_activities&#34;&gt;many things to do&lt;/a&gt; in and around Toronto. We still need to make the planning, but the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Niagara_Falls&#34;&gt;Niagara Falls&lt;/a&gt; are definitely on the list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, big thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.elys.com/home/&#34;&gt;Elysium Digital&lt;/a&gt;, a technology oriented consulting company for legal matters. Apparently they use Arch Linux for many things: on the desktop, in the server room, and in the forensic lab.   They emailed me to propose sponsoring my plane tickets, and they did.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uzbl, monitoring, AIF talks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/uzbl_monitoring_aif_talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2010 12:06:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/uzbl_monitoring_aif_talks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uzbl.org/news.php?id=25&#34;&gt;Uzbl lightningtalk @ fosdem 2010&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Open Source Monitoring tools lightning talk @ &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kangaroot-showcase.be/&#34;&gt;Kangaroot showcase&lt;/a&gt; 2009.  This one is password protected.  If you were a participant, you should have received the pass&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If all goes well, I&#39;ll be at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.archlinux.ca/archcon2010/&#34;&gt;ArchCon&lt;/a&gt; this summer, where I&#39;ll be doing these talks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.archlinux.ca/archcon2010/?p=67&#34;&gt;AIF: The Arch Installation Framework&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.archlinux.ca/archcon2010/?p=73&#34;&gt;Uzbl &amp; web interface tools which adhere to the unix philosophy&lt;/a&gt;. Whereas in the fosdem talk I had to focus a lot of information into a short timeslot, here I&#39;ll elaborate a bit more&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&#39;re not sure yet if those talks will get videotaped.&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Not working for Facebook</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/not_working_for_facebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2010 22:58:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/not_working_for_facebook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;They found my background interesting and thought I might be a good&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;fit for an &amp;ldquo;application operations engineer&amp;rdquo; position in Palo Alto, California. (it is&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;basically the link between their infrastructure engineering and operations/support&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;teams).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did a few technical interviews over phone with other app ops and engineers&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;from CA (about the Linux kernel, lowlevel userspace, mysql, memcached, networking, programming,&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;scalability, etc) and solved one of their optimisation puzzles.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;( I picked &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/careers/puzzles.php?puzzle_id=2&#34;&gt;usr bin crash&lt;/a&gt;.  Actually I wanted to do something with &amp;lt;a&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;href=&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://incubator.apache.org/thrift/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;thrift&#34;&gt;http://incubator.apache.org/thrift/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;thrift&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt; but &amp;lt;a&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;href=&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mail-archives.apache.org/mod_mbox/incubator-thrift-user/200911.mbox/%3C20091122202901.1f425b7f@plaetinck.be%3E&amp;quot;&amp;gt;I&#34;&gt;http://mail-archives.apache.org/mod_mbox/incubator-thrift-user/200911.mbox/%3C20091122202901.1f425b7f@plaetinck.be%3E&amp;quot;&amp;gt;I&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;couldn&amp;rsquo;t get it to compile&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The technical interviews went well but then I had&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;another interview which was about handling support.  As I have no experience&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;in setting up support frameworks and procedures to hand off to separate&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;support teams, I was/am not good enough for this position.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then they suggested a role as site reliability engineer for the office in Dublin, which is more about&lt;br /&gt;

troubleshooting, monitoring and systems management/automation.&lt;br /&gt;

So I did some more interviews with SRE&#39;s and engineers from the London office and&lt;br /&gt;

from Palo Alto.  Similar subjects as before, but with more of an operations/support touch to it.&lt;br /&gt;

These also went well, except the last one, which was more about things less related to&lt;br /&gt;

high-performance/scalability such as nfs, pam and ldap.&lt;br /&gt;

I think I missed too many questions on the last interview.  I could come up&lt;br /&gt;

with some excuses such as me being tired (it was the evening before our &lt;a

href=&#34;http://www.kangaroot-showcase.be/&#34;&gt;Kangaroot showcase&lt;/a&gt; event, and&lt;br /&gt;

the call being late - Facebook HR messed up a timezone conversion) but fact&lt;br /&gt;

of the matter is: I have little experience with such &#34;office ;-)&#34; stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So after 8 interviews over phone (each one about 40-60 minutes), spanning&lt;br /&gt;

about 2 months, they let me know they would not go forward with me.&lt;br /&gt;

That was late december, I asked for some feedback but haven&#39;t heard from&lt;br /&gt;

them since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bottomline: it sounded quite nice but I&#39;m pretty &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ted.com/talks/dan_gilbert_asks_why_are_we_happy.html&#34;&gt;happy&lt;/a&gt; with my current life in Belgium.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fosdem 2010</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/fosdem_2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2010 17:10:16 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/fosdem_2010/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fosdem.org&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/files/blog/fosdem/going-to-2010.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;I&#39;m going to FOSDEM, the Free and Open Source Software Developers&#39; European Meeting&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ll be presenting a &lt;a href=&#34;http://fosdem.org/2010/schedule/events/uzbl&#34;&gt;lightning talk&lt;/a&gt; about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uzbl.org/&#34;&gt;uzbl&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;

Also, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.archlinux.org/&#34;&gt;Arch Linux&lt;/a&gt; guys Roman, JGC, Thomas and me will hang out at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://fosdem.org/2010/schedule/devrooms/distributions&#34;&gt;distro miniconf&lt;/a&gt;.  We might join the &lt;a href=&#34;http://fosdem.org/2010/schedule/events/dist_infrastructure&#34;&gt;infrastructure round-table&lt;/a&gt; panel, but there is no concrete information yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More stuff I&#39;m looking forward to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://fosdem.org/2010/schedule/phone&#34;&gt;fosdem maemo application&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://fosdem.org/2010/schedule/events/dist_mirrorbrain&#34;&gt;mirrorbrain. a topic often discussed at Arch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://fosdem.org/2010/schedule/events/dist_clicfs&#34;&gt;clicfs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://fosdem.org/2010/news/fosdem-multiplies-things-10&#34;&gt;a 2nd fries van!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://fosdem.org/2010/schedule/events/openpcf&#34;&gt;openpcf&lt;/a&gt; (how would this compare to puppet et al?)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://fosdem.org/2010/schedule/events/asterisk&#34;&gt;asterisk development&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://fosdem.org/2010/schedule/events/csync&#34;&gt;csync&lt;/a&gt; (reminds me of my own &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/Dieterbe/ddm&#34;&gt;ddm&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://fosdem.org/2010/schedule/events/nosql_mongodb_intro&#34;&gt;mongodb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://fosdem.org/2010/schedule/events/nosql_cassandra&#34;&gt;cassandra&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://fosdem.org/2010/schedule/events/nosql_mapreduce_couchdb&#34;&gt;map/reduce in nosql vs sql on rdms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://fosdem.org/2010/schedule/events/linuxkernelpatch&#34;&gt;writing a patch for linux&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://fosdem.org/2010/schedule/events/systemtap&#34;&gt;systemtap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://fosdem.org/2010/schedule/events/scalingfacebook&#34;&gt;scaling facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m suprised myself how there are much more topics of interest to me then last year, and I&#39;m not sure if the program is even finished.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About the maemo summit 2009 and the nokia n900</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/about_the_maemo_summit_2009_and_the_nokia_n900/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2009 21:20:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/about_the_maemo_summit_2009_and_the_nokia_n900/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The talks were diverse, but interesting (duh?).  I will especially remember the kickoff with its fancy visual effects and loud music that set the mood straight for the entire weekend.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best moment was, of course, when it was announced that &lt;strong&gt;every summit participant would receive a n900.  Uncontrolled hapiness all around. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had been hoping to buy/preorder the device at the event, with maybe a nice reduction.  But I didn&amp;rsquo;t dare to hope on getting a device in my hands just like that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how does this work?&lt;br /&gt;

Basically, all summit attendees were offered the following deal (I don&#39;t think anyone passed it).  I paraphrase:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;User gets to use n900 preproduction model until end of April 2010 or earlier if Nokia wants so.&lt;br /&gt;

User provides feedback to Nokia in any form, which Nokia gets ownership of.&lt;br /&gt;

User may not copy/reverse engineer/decompile device/material/software.  But other then that he can fully use it, hack (on) it and share information about it.&lt;br /&gt;

No warranty or any form of compensation if the device blows up your house, breaks your arm, or submits your personal data to pastebin.com&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Definitely fair enough I would say.  I&#39;ll surely stick to my end of the deal and provide them a good dose of feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first experiences?  Here are the main things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I think the hardware is definitive, the software probably isn&#39;t.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Meets all expectations:

&lt;ul&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Complete debian-based mini-pc which fits in pocket easily.  A screen (800x480) which shows normal webpages just fine, no need for smaller pages.  Typing on keyboard is a lot slower then on a netbook.  For me the device could have been bigger so I could do 10-finger typing (I would call using a headset anyway), but I&#39;m sure many people like the small formfactor&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;A userland we are used to: glibc, sysvinit, dbus, gstreamer, bluez, gtk, HAL, apt, and so on&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Very nice and easy UI, high performance multitasking, 3D, many nice details seem to be implemented just when you need them, ...&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Not just a &#34;OS + apps&#34; but everything can be (and usually is) integrated: i.e. contact book with the various means to reach a contact (jabber/sms/skype/cellular call/..).  when you call someone it will choose skype or cellular, whichever is best. (this probably expands to SIP and whichever means more applications will bring).  Contacts with birthdays show up in the calendar, etc.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Quite smooth UI. Sometimes a bit of stutter in multitask view when closing or switching apps (but hey, nothing my real PC doesn&#39;t do)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Many features for such a small form factor.  The hardware feels &#34;done&#34;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Battery lasts long enough.   About 30 hours for light to medium use on a new device&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;Slight nuisances, mostly with the software:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The microB browser needs some polishing.  It hangs when the wifi goes away&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Some lack of consistency in UI across maemo interface and various apps (scrolling behaviour is sometimes different, &#34;just start typing to initiate search&#34; doesn&#39;t apply everywhere) &lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Hard to open back cover and to remove battery &lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Shell (ash) history does not (always?) get saved&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;No tools such as less, sed, curl, awk, ... by default.  No packages for them yet&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Maps application feels incomplete.  It&#39;s not a navigation system like Tomtom (and a Nokia guy told me they aren&#39;t aiming for that)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;It continously tries looking for network when it can&#39;t find any, even though I keep saying no&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m keeping a detailed list of all issues I encounter, which I&#39;ll report on the bugtracker.&lt;br /&gt;

Until now all issues I found are small, and most are fixable in a short timespan so I think the &#34;real&#34; devices will be there soon.&lt;br /&gt;

I&#39;m definitely looking forward playing more with it and hacking it.&lt;br /&gt;

And most of all, I think I will actually begin trusting this device enough to maintain my contacts, calendar, .. and to actually use the features it brings (instead of for example ssh&#39;ing to home and chatting from there)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great work Nokia, you guys rock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;** update: 13-10-2009: updated the battery uptime number to 30 hours.  I measured it for real this time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nokia n900 &amp; maemo summit 2009</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/nokia_n900_and_maemo_summit_2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2009 17:40:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/nokia_n900_and_maemo_summit_2009/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, something like a netbook, but really portable, and that can also do telephony stuff.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nokia&amp;rsquo;s recently announced &lt;a href=&#34;http://maemo.nokia.com/n900/&#34;&gt;n900&lt;/a&gt; seems to be very close to what I&amp;rsquo;m looking for.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It could have been a tad bigger (to make typing easier) but other then that it looks perfect: powerful, high resolution display, Linux with a &amp;ldquo;usual&amp;rdquo; userspace (unlike Android) to give me all freedom I&amp;rsquo;m looking for, keyboard, plenty of space and many goodies such as wifi, a-gps, fm receiver/transmitter, IR, bluetooth, digital camera, tv-out and so on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This device has ignited my interest in Maemo and all things related so I&#39;ll be in Amsterdam on October 9-10-11, at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.maemo.org/Maemo_Summit_2009&#34;&gt;Maemo summit 2009&lt;/a&gt;.  I was lucky enough to score a place in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ibishotel.com/gb/hotel-1556-ibis-amsterdam-centre/index.shtml&#34;&gt;ibis hotel Amsterdam&lt;/a&gt;, as Nokia has reserved more rooms then they could fill with invited speakers and own personnel ;-)&lt;br /&gt;

I&#39;m hoping it will be possible to buy a device at the conference.  The timing would be perfect.  Nokia seems to be a really cool company and so far, they haven&#39;t disappointed yet...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somewhat related: a &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.maemo.org/Mer&#34;&gt;Mer (maemo alternative)&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://gitorious.org/~lbt&#34;&gt;developer&lt;/a&gt; told me he was very interested in making &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uzbl.org/&#34;&gt;uzbl&lt;/a&gt; available on Mer, so he did just that. I&#39;m curious myself how usable uzbl will be on the n900. Only one way to find out :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wishlist</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/wishlist/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2009 16:22:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/wishlist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/registry/wishlist/2K78V4LHLYBD&#34;&gt;wishlist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>