<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>foss on Dieter&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/foss/</link>
    <description>Recent content in foss on Dieter&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2011 22:32:12 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/foss/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Poor mans pickle implementations benchmark</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/poor_mans_pickle_implementations_benchmark/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2011 22:32:12 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/poor_mans_pickle_implementations_benchmark/</guid>
      
      <description></description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where are the new Arch Linux release images?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/where_are_the_new_arch_linux_images/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2011 21:29:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/where_are_the_new_arch_linux_images/</guid>
      
      <description></description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dvcs-autosync: An open source dropbox clone... well.. almost</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/dvcs-autosync_an_opensource_dropbox_clone_well_almost/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2011 21:48:56 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/dvcs-autosync_an_opensource_dropbox_clone_well_almost/</guid>
      
      <description>I found the Dvcs-autosync project on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://lists.madduck.net/listinfo/vcs-home&#34;&gt;vcs-home&lt;/a&gt; mailing list,
which btw is a great list for folks who are doing stuff like maintaining their home directory in a vcs.
&lt;br/&gt;In short:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;simple python tool (600 sloc), works with your dvcs of choice (mainly tested/used with git)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;watches for inotify events, performs commits on changes (coalesces some changes together)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;synchronizes with other clones (remotes), uses xmpp for push notifications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;let&#39;s you know what&#39;s going on through libnotify popups or whatever&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mayrhofer.eu.org/dvcs-autosync&#34;&gt;home page: http://mayrhofer.eu.org/dvcs-autosync&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://gitorious.org/dvcs-autosync/dvcs-autosync&#34;&gt;dvcs-autosync gitorious repo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://lists.madduck.net/pipermail/vcs-home/2011-March/000314.html&#34;&gt;initial announcement on vcs-home&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
Use cases:
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why rewriting git history? And why should commits be in imperative present tense?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/why-rewriting-git-history-and-why-commits-imperative-present-tense/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2011 18:27:35 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/why-rewriting-git-history-and-why-commits-imperative-present-tense/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
There are tons of articles describing &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; you can rewrite history with git, but they do not answer &#34;&lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; should I do it?&#34;.
A similar question is &#34;what are the tradeoffs / how do I apply this in my distributed workflow?&#34;.
&lt;br/&gt;Also, git developers strongly encourage/command you to write commit message in imperative present tense, but do not say why.  So, why?
&lt;br/&gt;I&#39;ll try to answer these to the best of my abilities, largely based on how I see things.  I won&#39;t get too detailed (there are enough manuals and tutorials for the exact concepts and commands).
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Libui-sh: a library providing UI functions for shell scripts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/libui-sh_a_library_providing_ui_functions_for_shell_scripts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2010 22:59:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/libui-sh_a_library_providing_ui_functions_for_shell_scripts/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
== A library providing UI functions for shell scripts ==&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you write bash/shell scripts, do you write your own error/debug/logging/abort functions?&lt;br /&gt;
Logic that requests the user to input a boolean, string, password, selection out of a list,&lt;br /&gt;
date/time, integer, ... ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Libui-sh is written to take care of all that.&lt;br /&gt;
libui-sh is meant to a be a general-purpose UI abstraction library for shell scripts.&lt;br /&gt;
Low impact, easy to use, but still flexible.&lt;br /&gt;
cli by default, can optionally use ncurses dialogs as well.&lt;br /&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rsyncbench, an rsync benchmarking tool</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/rsyncbench_an_rsync_benchmarking_tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2010 09:38:12 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/rsyncbench_an_rsync_benchmarking_tool/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Background info:&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m currently in the process of evaluating (V)PS hosting providers and backup solutions.  The idea being: I want a (V)PS to run my stuff, which doesn&#39;t need much disk space,&lt;br /&gt;
but in the meantime it might be a good idea to look for online backup solutions (oops did I say &#34;online&#34;? I meant &#34;cloud&#34;), like on the (V)PS itself, or maybe as a separate solution.&lt;br /&gt;
But I&#39;ve got some diverse amount of data (my personal data is mostly a lot of small plaintext files, my mom has a windows VM for which I considered syncing the entire vdi file)&lt;br /&gt;
At this point the biggest contenders are &lt;a href=&#34;http://linode.com/&#34;&gt;Linode&lt;/a&gt; (which offers quite some flexibility and management tools, but becomes expensive when you want extra disk space (2$/month*GB), &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rackspace.com/apps/backup_and_collaboration/data_backup_software/&#34;&gt;Rackspace backup&lt;/a&gt; gives you 10GB for 5$/month, but they have nice backup tools so I could only backup the important files from within the windows VM (~200MB), and then there&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hetzner.de/&#34;&gt;Hetzner&lt;/a&gt;, which offers powerful physical private servers with a lot of storage (160GB) for 29eur/month, but less flexibility (I.e. kvm-over-ip costs an extra 15eur/month)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another issue, given the limited capacity of Belgian internet connections, I needed to figure out how much bandwith rsync really needs, so I can calculate if the duration of a backup run including syncing the full vdi file is still reasonable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I couldn&#39;t find an rsync benchmarking tool, so I wrote my own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Features:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;simple&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;non invasive: you specify the target and destination hosts (just localhost is fine too), and file locations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;measures time spent, bytes sent (measured with tcpdump), and data sent (rsync&#39;s statistics which takes compression into account)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;supports plugins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;generates png graphs using Gnuplot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;two current plugins: one using files of various sizes, both randomly generated (/dev/urandom) and easily compressable (/dev/zero), does some use cases like initial sync, second sync (no-op), and syncing with a data block appended and prepended.  The other plugin collects vdi files from rsnapshot directories and measures the rsyncing from each image to the next&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An rss2email fork that sucks less</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/an_rss2email_fork_that_sucks_less/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2010 20:33:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/an_rss2email_fork_that_sucks_less/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.allthingsrss.com/rss2email/&#34;&gt;Rss2email&lt;/a&gt; is a great tool.  I like getting all my news messages in my mailbox and using smtp to make the &#34;news delivery&#34; process more robust makes sense.&lt;br /&gt;
However, there are some things I didn&#39;t like about it so I made a &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/Dieterbe/rss2email/&#34;&gt;github repo&lt;/a&gt; where I maintain an alternative version which (imho) contains several useful improvements, both for end users and for developers/downstreams.&lt;br /&gt;
Also, this was a nice opportunity for me to improve my python skills :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is how it compares:&lt;br /&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What the open source community can learn from Devops</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/what_the_open_source_community_can_learn_from_devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2010 22:26:22 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/what_the_open_source_community_can_learn_from_devops/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Being active as both a developer and ops person in the professional life, and both an open source developer and packager in my spare time, I noticed some common ground between both worlds, and I think the open source community can learn from the Devops movement which is solving problems in the professional tech world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the sake of getting a point across, I&#39;ll simplify some things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;First, a crash course on Devops...&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>the &#34;Community Contributions&#34; section on the Arch Linux forums is a goldmine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the_community_contributions_section_on_the_arch_linux_forums_is_a_goldmine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2010 22:11:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the_community_contributions_section_on_the_arch_linux_forums_is_a_goldmine/</guid>
      
      <description>The Community contributions subforum of the Arch Linux forums is awesome.
It is the birthplace of many applications, most of them not Arch Linux specific.
File managers, media players, browsers, window managers, text editors, todo managers, and so on. Many shell scripts, urxvt extensions and dwm patches aswell.
Most of the apps are designed after suckless/KISS principles, but there are also some GUI programs.
If you like to discover new apps and tools, check it out.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Restoring ssh connections on resume</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/restoring_ssh_connections_on_resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2010 18:11:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/restoring_ssh_connections_on_resume/</guid>
      
      <description>I use pm-utils for hibernation support.
It has a hooks system which can execute stuff upon hibernate/suspend/thaw/resume/..., but they run as root.
If you want to run stuff as a regular user you could do something like
su $user -c &amp;lt;command&amp;gt;..but these commands have no access to your user environment.
In my user environment I have a variable which I need access to, namely SSH_AUTH_SOCK, which points to my agent which has some unlocked ssh keys.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fosdem 2010</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/fosdem_2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2010 17:10:16 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/fosdem_2010/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ll be at fosdem - 10th edition - again this year.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fosdem.org&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/files/blog/fosdem/going-to-2010.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;I&#39;m going to FOSDEM, the Free and Open Source Software Developers&#39; European Meeting&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ll be presenting a &lt;a href=&#34;http://fosdem.org/2010/schedule/events/uzbl&#34;&gt;lightning talk&lt;/a&gt; about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uzbl.org/&#34;&gt;uzbl&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
Also, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.archlinux.org/&#34;&gt;Arch Linux&lt;/a&gt; guys Roman, JGC, Thomas and me will hang out at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://fosdem.org/2010/schedule/devrooms/distributions&#34;&gt;distro miniconf&lt;/a&gt;.  We might join the &lt;a href=&#34;http://fosdem.org/2010/schedule/events/dist_infrastructure&#34;&gt;infrastructure round-table&lt;/a&gt; panel, but there is no concrete information yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More stuff I&#39;m looking forward to:</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Opening files automatically on mainstream Linux desktops</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/opening_files_automatically_on_mainstream_linux_desktops/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2009 19:43:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/opening_files_automatically_on_mainstream_linux_desktops/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Xfce/Gnu/Linux works amazingly well on my moms workstation, with one exception: opening files automatically with the correct program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two biggest culprits are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gtk&#39;s &#34;open file with&#34; dialog: if any Gtk program doesn&#39;t know how to open a file it brings up this dialog that is horrible to use.  You can search through your entire VFS for the right executable.  No thumbnails, no usage of .desktop files, $PATH, autocompletion and not even limiting the scope to directories such as /usr/bin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mozilla software such as Firefox and Thunderbird: they only seem to differentiate files by their mimetype, not by extension.  There are add-ons to make it easier to edit these preferences, but eventually you&#39;re in a dead end because you get files with correct extensions but unuseful mimetimes (application/octet-stream)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily the fd.o guys have come up with &lt;a href=&#34;http://standards.freedesktop.org/desktop-entry-spec/desktop-entry-spec-latest.html&#34;&gt;.desktop files&lt;/a&gt;.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snip: a dead-simple but quite powerful text expander and more</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/snip_a_dead-simple_but_quite_powerful_text_expander_and_more/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2009 20:22:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/snip_a_dead-simple_but_quite_powerful_text_expander_and_more/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Inspired by &lt;a href=&#34;http://bbs.archlinux.org/viewtopic.php?id=71938&#34;&gt;Snippy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://lifehacker.com/351285/automate-repetitive-typing-with-snippits&#34;&gt;snippits&lt;/a&gt;, I wrote a simple tool called &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/Dieterbe/snip&#34;&gt;snip&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
It helps you to automatically fill in text for you (which can be dynamically created) and/or to perform custom keypresses and operations.&lt;br /&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arch Linux 2009.08 &amp; Froscon 2009</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/arch_linux_2009.08_and_froscon_2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2009 12:36:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/arch_linux_2009.08_and_froscon_2009/</guid>
      
      <description>So, the Arch Linux 2009.08 release is now behind us, nicely on schedule.
I hope people will like AIF because it was a lot of work and we didn&#39;t receive much feedback. I personally like it to apply my fancy backup restoration approach.
But I&#39;m sure if more people would look at the code we would find quite some design and implementation things that could be improved. (With uzbl I was amazed how much difference it can make if many people all have ideas and opinions about every little detail)</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mysql status variables caveats</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/mysql_status_variables_caveats/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2009 11:33:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/mysql_status_variables_caveats/</guid>
      
      <description>While setting up Zenoss and reading Mysql documentation about status variables I learned:
All select_* variables (&#34;Select statistics&#34; graph in Zenoss) are actually about joins, not (all) selects. This also explains why there is no clear relation to com_select (which shows the amount of selects). (&#34;Command statistics:selects&#34; graph in Zenoss) Com_select does not denote all incoming select commands. If you have a hit on your query cache, com_select is not incremented.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zenoss &amp; Mysql monitoring</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/zenoss_and_mysql_monitoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2009 10:35:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/zenoss_and_mysql_monitoring/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been playing with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zenoss.com/&#34;&gt;Zenoss&lt;/a&gt; (2.4) for the first time.  Here are my thoughts:</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uzbl.  A browser that adheres to the unix philosophy.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/uzbl_a_browser_that_adheres_to_the_unix_philosophy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2009 23:02:37 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/uzbl_a_browser_that_adheres_to_the_unix_philosophy/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I need a browser that is fast, not bloated, stores my data (bookmarks, history, account settings, preferences, ...) in simple text files that I can keep under version control, something that does not reinvent the wheel, something that I can control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I could not find it.&lt;br /&gt;
So I started the &lt;a href=&#34;http://bbs.archlinux.org/viewtopic.php?id=70700&amp;amp;p=1&#34;&gt;uzbl browser&lt;/a&gt; project.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poor mans dmenu benchmark</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/poor_mans_dmenu_benchmark/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2009 11:25:26 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/poor_mans_dmenu_benchmark/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wanted to know how responsive &lt;a href=&#34;http://tools.suckless.org/dmenu&#34;&gt;dmenu&lt;/a&gt; and awk, sort, uniq are on a 50MB file (625000 entries of 80 1-byte chars each).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fosdem 2009</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/fosdem_2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2009 21:20:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/fosdem_2009/</guid>
      
      <description>
I&#39;m particulary interested in:
The out-of-the-box concepts of Exherbo. I hope to see more things like this. Various talks at OpenSuse about distribution development, their build service, etc. tools such as func and puppet. syslinux, upstart, ext4 etc. Some mysql stuff and the filesystem i/o from a db perspective talk. </description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CakePHP and a paradigm shift to a code generation based approach?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/cakephp_and_a_paradigm_shift_to_a_code_generation_based_approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2009 22:16:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/cakephp_and_a_paradigm_shift_to_a_code_generation_based_approach/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At my &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/jobhunt_over&#34;&gt;new job&lt;/a&gt;, I&#39;m writing a quite full-featured web application.&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;ve choosen to use CakePHP.&lt;br /&gt;
Why? Well, it may be 2 years since I last used it, but I&#39;ve followed the project and it&#39;s planet, and it seems to have matured and gained even more monumentum.&lt;br /&gt;
I want to use something that is widely used so there is plenty of stuff available for it, it&#39;s RAD, it&#39;s flexible and powerful.&lt;br /&gt;
I noticed things such as CLI support and documentation have improved tremendously too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I find that still, the recommended (or at least &#34;most commonly used&#34;) practices are not as efficient as they could be, and that emphasis is placed on the wrong aspects.&lt;br /&gt;
See, even though the &lt;a href=&#34;http://book.cakephp.org/view/113/Code-Generation-with-Bake&#34;&gt;bake&lt;/a&gt; tool has come a long way since I last used it, it&#39;s still used to &#34;generate some standard models/controllers/views&#34; and the developer can take it from there [further editing the resulting files himself].&lt;br /&gt;
Finetuning generated code by editing the templates (in fact, only views have templates; the php code of models and controllers is hardcoded in the scripts that generate them), is still an obscure practice...&lt;br /&gt;
Also, there are very few commandline switches (Right now you can choose your app dir, whether you want to bake a model,controller or view, and it&#39;s name.)&lt;br /&gt;
All other things (validation rules, associatons, index/view/edit/add actions/views, which components, overwrite yes/no etc) are all handled interactively.&lt;br /&gt;
There are also some smaller enoyances such as when you specify one option like the name of the model, it assumes you don&#39;t want interactivity and produces a model containing nothing more then the class definition and the membervariable $name, which is usually worthless.&lt;br /&gt;
One thing that is pretty neat though, If you update $this-&gt;recursive in a model, the baked views will contain stuff for the associated things.  But so much more could be done...&lt;br /&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jobhunt over.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/jobhunt_over/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2008 18:07:35 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/jobhunt_over/</guid>
      
      <description>What better way to launch the new year then starting to work as a System Engineer/Developer for a consulting firm where everyone breathes Linux and Open Source?
Next week I&#39;ll start at Kangaroot. Woohoo.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>new AIF release</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/new_aif_release/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2008 09:50:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/new_aif_release/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My holidays present for Arch devs and users: AIF alpha-0.6 !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* Changes since alpha 0.5:</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AIF: the brand new Arch Linux Installation Framework</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/aif_the_brand_new_arch_linux_installation_framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2008 11:45:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/aif_the_brand_new_arch_linux_installation_framework/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I started thinking about writing my own automatic installer that would set up my system exactly the way I want.&lt;br /&gt;
(See &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/rethinking_the_backup_paradigm_a_higher-level_approach&#34; title=&#34;/rethinking_the_backup_paradigm_a_higher-level_approach&#34;&gt;rethinking_the_backup_paradigm_a_higher-level...&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I looked at the official Arch install scripts to see if I could reuse parts of their code, but unfortunately the code was just one big chunk of bash code with the main program and &#34;flow control&#34; (you must first do this step, then that), UI-code (dialogs etc) and backend logic (create filesystems, ...) all mangled up and mixed very closely together.&lt;br /&gt;
Functionality-wise the installer works fine, but I guess the code behind it is the result of years of adding features and quick fixes without refactoring, making it impossible to reuse any of the code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I started to write &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/Dieterbe/aif/&#34;&gt;AIF: the Arch Linux Installation Framework&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Handling a remote rename/move with Git</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/handling_a_remote_rename_or_move_with_git/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2008 11:29:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/handling_a_remote_rename_or_move_with_git/</guid>
      
      <description>I recently had to rename a repo on my Github account. Github has made this very easy but it&#39;s just one side of the issue. Obviously you must also update any references to this remote in other clones, otherwise pushes, fetches etc won&#39;t work anymore.
You can do this in two ways:
open .git/config and modify the url for the remote manually git remote rm origin &amp;amp;&amp;amp; git remote add origin git@github.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dautostart, a standalone freedesktop-compliant application starter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/dautostart_a_standalone_freedesktop-compliant_application_starter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2008 13:26:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/dautostart_a_standalone_freedesktop-compliant_application_starter/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I couldn&#39;t find a standalone application/script that implements &lt;a href=&#34;http://standards.freedesktop.org/autostart-spec/autostart-spec-latest.html&#34;&gt;freedesktop compliant (XDG based) autostarting&lt;/a&gt; of applications, so I decided to write my own.&lt;br /&gt;
The project is at &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/Dieterbe/dautostart&#34; title=&#34;http://github.com/Dieterbe/dautostart&#34;&gt;http://github.com/Dieterbe/dautostart&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now, all the basics seem to work (except &#34;Autostart Of Applications After Mount&#34; of the spec).&lt;br /&gt;
It&#39;s probably not bugfree.  I hacked it together in a few hours (but it works for me :-).   Bugreports welcome!&lt;br /&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m done with Gnome/Gconf</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/im_done_with_gnome_and_gconf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2008 22:01:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/im_done_with_gnome_and_gconf/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m managing my ~ in svn but using gnome &amp;amp; gconf makes this rather hard.&lt;br /&gt;
They mangle cache data together with user data and user preferences and spread that mix over several directories in your home  (.gconf, .gnome2 etc).&lt;br /&gt;
The .gconf directory is the worst.  This is where many applications store all their stuff.   User preferences but also various %gconf.xml files, which seem to be updated automatically everytime &#39;something&#39; happens:  They keep track of timestamps for various events such as when you press numlock or become available on pidgin.&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m fine with the fact they do that.  I&#39;m sure it enables them to provide some additional functionality.  But they need to do it in clearly separated places (such as &lt;a href=&#34;http://standards.freedesktop.org/basedir-spec/basedir-spec-0.6.html&#34;&gt;xdg&#39;s&lt;/a&gt; $XDG_CACHE_HOME directory)</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DDM v0.4 released</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ddm_v04_released/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2008 16:21:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ddm_v04_released/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;DDM v0.4 has been released.&lt;br /&gt;
Since the last release many, many things have been changed/fixed/added.&lt;br /&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My projects are on github now</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my_projects_are_on_github_now/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2008 11:40:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my_projects_are_on_github_now/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve put my (somewhat interesting) projects on &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
Git is a damn cool VCS for distributed development, and I think Github integrates with it really nicely, adding some useful aspects for following and collaborating on projects.&lt;br /&gt;
The projects I have migrated to my &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Dieterbe&#34;&gt;GitHub profile&lt;/a&gt; are:</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Requirements for the perfect GTD tool</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/requirements_for_the_perfect_gtd_tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2008 16:04:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/requirements_for_the_perfect_gtd_tool/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been reading &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Getting_Things_Done&#34;&gt;GTD&lt;/a&gt; lately and it&#39;s absolutely a great and inspiring book.&lt;br /&gt;
Having made my home office space into a real &lt;i&gt;Zen&lt;/i&gt; I want to start implementing GTD in my digital life but it seems very hard to find a good GTD tool that fully implements GTD. (even though there are a lot of tools out there)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most interesting ones (each for different reasons) I&#39;ve looked at so far are &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thinkingrock.com.au/index.php&#34;&gt;Thinkingrock&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rousette.org.uk/projects/&#34;&gt;tracks&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://gna.org/projects/yagtd/&#34;&gt;yagtd&lt;/a&gt; (the latter requiring most work before it does everything I need, but it&#39;s also the most easy to dive into the code base). I&#39;m keeping my eyes open because there are certainly more things to discover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though there are probably no applications out there that can do everything I want, I just wanted to share my feature-wishlist.  These are the requirements I find that a really good tool should comply with:&lt;br /&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the Netlog Developer Pages</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/announcing_the_netlog_developer_pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2008 12:39:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/announcing_the_netlog_developer_pages/</guid>
      
      <description>At work, we&#39;ve setup the Netlog Developer Pages
It is the place where you can/will find all information around our OpenSocial implementation, our own API, skin development, sample code and so on.
We&#39;ve also launched a group where you can communicate with fellow developers and Netlog employees.
The page also features a blog where you can follow what is going on in the Netlog Tech team.
PS: We&#39;ve also updated our jobs page</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DDM : a Distributed Data Manager</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ddm_a_distributed_data_manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2008 20:28:16 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ddm_a_distributed_data_manager/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;UPDATE: this information is outdated.  See &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/Dieterbe/ddm/tree/master&#34; title=&#34;http://github.com/Dieterbe/ddm/tree/master&#34;&gt;http://github.com/Dieterbe/ddm/tree/master&lt;/a&gt; for latest information.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have multiple sets of data (e.g.: music, images, documents, movies, ...) and you use these on more then one system ( e.g. a laptop and a file server) then you probably also have some &#39;rules&#39; on how you use these on your systems.  For example after capturing new images you maybe put them on your laptop first but you like to sync them to your file server frequently.  On the other hand you also want all your high-res images (stored on the server) available for editing on the laptop, and to make it more complicated you might have the same images in a smaller format on your server (for gallery programs etc.) and want these (or a select few albums of them) available on the road. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more different types of data you have and the more you have specific work flows the harder it becomes to keep your data as up to date as possible and consistent on your boxes.  You could manually rsync/(s)cp your data but you end up in having a mess (at least that&#39;s how it turned out on my boxes). Putting everything under version control is great for text files and such, but it&#39;s not an option for bigger (binary) files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to keep all my stuff neatly organised in my home directories and I want to create good work flows with as minimum hassle as possible, so I decided to write DDM: the Distributed Data Manager.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tweaking Lighttpd stat() performance with fcgi-stat-accel</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/tweaking_lighttpd_stat_performance_with_fcgi-stat-accel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2008 21:12:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/tweaking_lighttpd_stat_performance_with_fcgi-stat-accel/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you serve lots of (small) files with Lighttpd you might notice you&#39;re not getting the throughput you would expect.  Other factors (such as latencies because of the random read patterns ) aside, a real show stopper is the stat() system call, which is a blocking system call ( no parallelism ).  Some clever guys thought of a way to solve this : a fastcgi program that does a stat(), so when it returns Lighty doesn&#39;t have to wait because the stat information will be in the Linux cache.  And in the meanwhile your Lighty thread can do other stuff.  
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m not going to Fosdem 2008</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/im_not_going_to_fosdem_2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2008 20:37:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/im_not_going_to_fosdem_2008/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wish I could put this on my webpage :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fosdem.org&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/files/blog/fosdem/going-to-2008.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;I&#39;m going to FOSDEM, the Free and Open Source Software Developers&#39; European Meeting&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gtk dialogs for (shell)scripts with zenity and the ask-pass gui tools for ssh-add</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/gtk_dialogs_for_shell_scripts_with_zenity_and_the_ask-pass_gui_tools_for_ssh-add/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2007 18:45:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/gtk_dialogs_for_shell_scripts_with_zenity_and_the_ask-pass_gui_tools_for_ssh-add/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Phew! where to start?  Probably at &lt;a href =&#34;http://www.chimeric.de/blog/2007/1107_mounting_external_truecrypt_volumes_interactively&#34;&gt;this blogpost&lt;/a&gt;.  It&#39;s about making it very easy to work with external encrypted volumes. I&#39;m not going to talk about the article itself but about a great tool i discovered thanks to it: Zenity. </description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nagios monitoring in your desktop panel aka Xfce Genmon panel plugin rules!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/nagios_monitoring_in_your_desktop_panel_aka_xfce_genmon_panel_plugin_rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2007 16:42:46 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/nagios_monitoring_in_your_desktop_panel_aka_xfce_genmon_panel_plugin_rules/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;FOSS is written by users, for users, and what I&#39;ve been doing/experiencing this afternoon is a perfect example of that.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assymetric keys instead of passwords for SSH authentication to increase security and convenience</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/assymetric_keys_instead_of_passwords_for_ssh_authentication_to_increase_security_and_convenience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2007 20:22:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/assymetric_keys_instead_of_passwords_for_ssh_authentication_to_increase_security_and_convenience/</guid>
      
      <description>I&#39;ve been using OpenSSH already for a while and although I&#39;ve seen mentions of &#34;public key authentication&#34; and &#34;RSA encryption&#34; several times in it&#39;s config files, I never decided to figure out what it did exactly, and stuck to password authentication. But now the guys at work explained how it works and after reading more about it, I&#39;m totally hooked on it!
It&#39;s a feature in ssh protocol version 2 (thus it&#39;s around for already a while, e.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The perfect GTK music player: can Exaile replace Amarok?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the_perfect_gtk_music_player_can_exaile_replace_amarok/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2007 12:50:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the_perfect_gtk_music_player_can_exaile_replace_amarok/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve always liked Amarok: it does everything I always wanted, &lt;em&gt; and more&lt;/em&gt;.  It looks perfect in every way ...&lt;br /&gt;
But .. it uses the QT library, and although there are tricks to make QT applications more fit in with your gtk desktop/theme it will never fit in perfectly, not only graphically but also because you still need to load the qt libraries when you want to listen to some music and it is built to interact with the KDE desktop environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I&#39;ve been looking for an alternative, a GTK application strong enough to actually be able to replace Amarok, the king of all software music players.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dAuth</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/dauth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2007 13:19:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/dauth/</guid>
      
      <description>dAuth is a secure authentication system for CakePHP.
It uses techniques such as the challenge-response paradigm, customizable multiple-stage password hashing, brute force (hammering) detection, session hijacking prevention etc.
Read all about it
You can download the files separately on the before mentioned page or get the tarball that somebody was kind enough to create.
(damn I&#39;m lazy today)
I don&#39;t maintain this any more!</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhpDeliciousClient, a php cli client to administer del.icio.us accounts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/phpdeliciousclient_a_php_cli_client_to_administer_delicious_accounts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2007 16:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/phpdeliciousclient_a_php_cli_client_to_administer_delicious_accounts/</guid>
      
      <description>PhpDeliciousClient is a console based client for doing maintenance on Del.icio.us accounts.
I wrote it because - to my knowledge - there currently is no good program (including the personalized del.icio.us web page itself) that lets you make changes to your del.icio.us data in a powerful, productive manner. (with data I primarily mean tags. Posts and bundles are considered less important).
You probably are familiar with the fact that a Delicious account (or any tag based meta data organizing system, for that matter) can soon become bloated: It gets filled with way too many tags.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhpDeliciousClient</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/php_delicious_client/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2007 13:52:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/php_delicious_client/</guid>
      
      <description>Introduction PhpDeliciousClient is a CLI program for administering your Delicous account. When you invoke it from the command line you have some methods to administer your tags and your posts.
It&#39;s written in PHP and uses Ed Eliot&#39;s PhpDelicous class to contact the del.icio.us api. (included in download)
PhpDeliciousClient is licensed under the GPL v2, while the PhpDelicious class is licensed under the BSD license.
Why? The main reason I started developing it is because administering your account on the del.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open source en softwarepatenten vanuit een ethisch perspectief</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/open_source_softwarepatenten_vanuit_ethisch_perspectief/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2007 00:53:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/open_source_softwarepatenten_vanuit_ethisch_perspectief/</guid>
      
      <description>Voor school moest ik een ethisch verslag schrijven.
Hier moesten 3 elementen in voorkomen:
Inleidende tekst / Persoonlijke reflectie over beroeps- en bedrijfsethiek Ethische beschouwingen bij het eindwerk Uitgebreidere verhandeling met ethische beschouwingen over een vraagstuk naar keuze uit het domein van wetenschap, techniek, beroeps- en bedrijfsleven. In mijn geval is dit vraagstuk naar keuze &#34;open source en softwarepatenten&#34; geworden Zoals sommigen onder jullie weten vind ik ethiek een heel belangrijk aspect in het leven en ik ben dan ook blij dat ik het issue van open source en softwarepatenten verder heb kunnen uitdiepen, want dit is iets waar ik in geinteresseerd ben.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I just became a &#34;System &amp; Network Architect&#34;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/i_just_became_a_system_and_network_architect/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2007 20:11:07 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/i_just_became_a_system_and_network_architect/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just signed my contract at &lt;a href=&#34;http://incrowd.be/&#34;&gt;Incrowd&lt;/a&gt;, the company behind sites such as &lt;a href=&#34;http://redbox.be/&#34;&gt;redbox&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebox.com/&#34;&gt;facebox&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will be working there in a team of all young, enthusiastic people.  Among those, some people are already familiar to me:  my old friend &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lievendekeyser.net/&#34;&gt;Lieven&lt;/a&gt; (we&#39;ve played in a band together but kept in touch afterwards) and my ex-classmate &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jurriaanpersyn.com/&#34;&gt;Jurriaan&lt;/a&gt;.  Both of them love their jobs btw :-).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My official title is &#34;System &amp;amp; Network architect&#34;.&lt;br /&gt;
Things I will be doing there is </description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fosdem 2007 review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/fosdem_2007_review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2007 21:02:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/fosdem_2007_review/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every year, during a special weekend in February, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ulb.ac.be/&#34;&gt;University Libre of Brussels&lt;/a&gt; suddenly becomes a little more geeky.&lt;br /&gt;
It&#39;s that time of the year when many European (and some inter-continental) colleagues join us at&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fosdem.org&#34;&gt;Fosdem: the Free and Open source Software Developers&#39; European Meeting&lt;/a&gt; (more info &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fosdem.org/about/fosdem&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My favorite bash tricks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my_favorite_bash_tricks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2007 23:38:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my_favorite_bash_tricks/</guid>
      
      <description>Hello everyone.
This post is about bash, the shell providing so many users easy access to the underlying power of their system.
(not bash the quote database, although i really like that website too ;-) )
Most people know the basics, but getting to know it better can really increase your productivity. And when that happens, you might start loving bash as much as I do ;-)
I assume you have a basic knowledge of bash, the history mechanism, and ~/.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello world!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/blogpost1_hello_world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2007 14:45:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/blogpost1_hello_world/</guid>
      
      <description>Finally, my own website...
I already wanted to get this up for a long time. My initial idea was writing (and styling) it all from scratch using the marvelous CakePHP framework along with an authentication system i wrote, dAuth.
However, due to my lack of time I decided to use the excellent drupal platform, of which I&#39;m quite sure will get the job done equally well, while drastically liberating my time, so I can invest it in other projects :-)</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
