<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>life on Dieter&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in life on Dieter&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2015 09:22:02 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Focusing on open source monitoring.  Joining raintank.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/focusing-on-open-source-monitoring-joining-raintank/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2015 09:22:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/focusing-on-open-source-monitoring-joining-raintank/</guid>
      
      <description>Vimeo is special.  It changed my life.
But interests, goals and ambitions change.
This post is about leaving, joining raintank, working remote while traveling, open source monitoring, startups, personal relations, litmus and Grafana alerting</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving to New York City</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/moving-to-nyc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2012 16:50:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/moving-to-nyc/</guid>
      
      <description>I have a one-way ticket to NYC on Sept. 21st. Vimeo HQ is in Manhattan, and practically the whole team works in the building so it makes sense for me to relocate and join them locally. I&#39;m looking forward to working with the colleagues face to face, but mainly I&#39;m looking forward to the experience of living in such a different place, and exploring the US. In fact, I already have some small trips planned (Hamptons NY, camping in Pennsylvania, skiing in New York this winter) with some friends I met last year in NY.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thailand, Berlin Velocity EU, NYC, Ghent and more metal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/thailand_berlin_velocity_nyc_ghent_metal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2012 18:10:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/thailand_berlin_velocity_nyc_ghent_metal/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been meaning to write about a lot of stuff in separate posts, but they kept getting delayed, so I&#39;ll just briefly share everything in one post.
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hitchhiking.. try it.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/hitchhiking_try_it/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2011 16:04:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/hitchhiking_try_it/</guid>
      
      <description>For the last few months, I&#39;ve started to actively use hitchhiking as a means to
travel between home and work.
What started as a &#34;I&#39;m not sure about this, it seems a bit awkward, but I do
want to know how it goes and feels, so I&#39;ll try it out once&#34; ended up being &#34;this is
great, I&#39;m doing it every day and loving it&#34;.
Here&#39;s why you should try it and why it may make your life more awesome.
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My metal band</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my_metalband/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2011 14:58:12 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my_metalband/</guid>
      
      <description>Since the audience of this blog is largely technical, I don&#39;t post much about other topics, but I feel it&#39;s time for a short summary about one of my &#34;real life projects&#34;. In the spring of 2009 I joined a progressive death metal band. I&#39;ve been drumming since I was 17, but during the last 2 years I&#39;ve been practising and rehearsing like never before.[1] When you hear yourself on tape for the first time, it&#39;s a bit of disillusionment as you suddenly hear every imperfection, many of which you didn&#39;t realise you had (or didn&#39;t think were very noticeable).</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can we build a simple, cross-distribution installation framework?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/can_we_build_a_simple_cross-distribution_installation_framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2011 23:46:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/can_we_build_a_simple_cross-distribution_installation_framework/</guid>
      
      <description>Today at Fosdem 2011 I did my talk Can we build a simple, cross-distribution installation framework? Basically, using the Arch Installation Framework as a starting point, along with the notion that most of the code is actually not Arch-specific I adressed other distros to check if there was any interest in sharing workload on the distribution-agnostic aspects of the framework. If other distros with a similar philosophy of little-abstractions/KISS would join, we would all reap the benefits of a simple, yet quite featureful installer.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dir 2011, Fosdem 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/dir_fosdem_2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 23:15:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/dir_fosdem_2011/</guid>
      
      <description>On February 4, I&#39;ll be in Amsterdam at DIR 2011, the 11th Dutch-Belgian Information Retrieval Workshop. After that, I&#39;m going to the devopsdinner and Fosdem beer event in Brussels. On february 5/6 of course, Fosdem itself. Looking forward to the systemd talk. On sunday I&#39;ll do a talk about simple shell based Gnu/Linux installers, like mentioned earlier I hope devs from other &#34;lightweight&#34;/kiss-style distro&#39;s will be present (Gentoo and other *too&#39;s, Crux, *ppix, .</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a search engine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/building_a_search_engine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2011 19:15:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/building_a_search_engine/</guid>
      
      <description>I started working at IBCN, the research group of the university of Ghent. I was looking to get back to the challenging world of high-performance and large-scale (web) applications, but I also wanted something more conceptual and researchy, rather then the highly hands-on dev- and ops work I&#39;ve been doing for a few years now. The Bom-vl project is pretty broad: it aims to make the Flemish cultural heritage media more useable by properly digitizing, archiving and making public the (currently mostly analog) archives from providers such as TV stations.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back from Canada, Archcon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/back_from_canada_archcon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2010 23:10:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/back_from_canada_archcon/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m back from Canada/Archcon, and it was great. I&#39;ve been in Toronto for 11 days, and visited Montreal for 3 days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Archcon&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Archcon was small (20-ish people).  (That&#39;s what you get for doing it in Canada ;), but very nice.&lt;br /&gt;
Interesting talks, informal, good vibe, decent logistics and catering.&lt;br /&gt;
This year it happened because Dusty and Ricardo actually just wanted to have a conference without worrying too much about the attendance,&lt;br /&gt;
next year we should do it again because Arch (conferences) rock(s), and because we need more visitors.  More central locations such as Seattle and Europe have been suggested.&lt;br /&gt;
Either way, next year both Judd (founder) and Aaron (current overlord) should be there. (this year they both had lame excuses like family reunions and &#34;almost getting married&#34;.  Congrats btw, Aaron!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was an absolute pleasure to meet some more of my fellow devs, and users.&lt;br /&gt;
Here is a pic from the group (unfortunately, a few are missing)</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Off to Toronto July 14-28, Archcon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/off_to_toronto_july_14-28_archcon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2010 11:34:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/off_to_toronto_july_14-28_archcon/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As mentioned &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/uzbl_monitoring_aif_talks&#34;&gt;earlier&lt;/a&gt;, I&#39;ll be at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.archlinux.ca/archcon2010/&#34;&gt;Archcon in Toronto&lt;/a&gt; in a few weeks.&lt;br /&gt;
It&#39;s a very small conference, and the first of its kind.  At the &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/froscon_2009_afterthoughts&#34;&gt;last FrOSCon&lt;/a&gt; we have been playing with the idea to hold an informal Arch conference in Europe, but those were just ideas.  Dusty and Ricardo beat us with an actual implementation.&lt;br /&gt;
This is great, and one of the milestones in Arch Linux history.  Which is why I want to be there and help making it better.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uzbl, monitoring, AIF talks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/uzbl_monitoring_aif_talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2010 12:06:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/uzbl_monitoring_aif_talks/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently did two talks, for which the videos are now online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uzbl.org/news.php?id=25&#34;&gt;Uzbl lightningtalk @ fosdem 2010&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open Source Monitoring tools lightning talk @ &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kangaroot-showcase.be/&#34;&gt;Kangaroot showcase&lt;/a&gt; 2009.  This one is password protected.  If you were a participant, you should have received the pass&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If all goes well, I&#39;ll be at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.archlinux.ca/archcon2010/&#34;&gt;ArchCon&lt;/a&gt; this summer, where I&#39;ll be doing these talks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.archlinux.ca/archcon2010/?p=67&#34;&gt;AIF: The Arch Installation Framework&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.archlinux.ca/archcon2010/?p=73&#34;&gt;Uzbl &amp; web interface tools which adhere to the unix philosophy&lt;/a&gt;. Whereas in the fosdem talk I had to focus a lot of information into a short timeslot, here I&#39;ll elaborate a bit more&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;re not sure yet if those talks will get videotaped.&lt;br /&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Not working for Facebook</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/not_working_for_facebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2010 22:58:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/not_working_for_facebook/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In november last year, I was contacted by Facebook HR.&lt;br /&gt;
They found my background interesting and thought I might be a good&lt;br /&gt;
fit for an &#34;application operations engineer&#34; position in Palo Alto, California. (it is&lt;br /&gt;
basically the link between their infrastructure engineering and operations/support&lt;br /&gt;
teams).</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fosdem 2010</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/fosdem_2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2010 17:10:16 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/fosdem_2010/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ll be at fosdem - 10th edition - again this year.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fosdem.org&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/files/blog/fosdem/going-to-2010.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;I&#39;m going to FOSDEM, the Free and Open Source Software Developers&#39; European Meeting&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ll be presenting a &lt;a href=&#34;http://fosdem.org/2010/schedule/events/uzbl&#34;&gt;lightning talk&lt;/a&gt; about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uzbl.org/&#34;&gt;uzbl&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
Also, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.archlinux.org/&#34;&gt;Arch Linux&lt;/a&gt; guys Roman, JGC, Thomas and me will hang out at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://fosdem.org/2010/schedule/devrooms/distributions&#34;&gt;distro miniconf&lt;/a&gt;.  We might join the &lt;a href=&#34;http://fosdem.org/2010/schedule/events/dist_infrastructure&#34;&gt;infrastructure round-table&lt;/a&gt; panel, but there is no concrete information yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More stuff I&#39;m looking forward to:</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About the maemo summit 2009 and the nokia n900</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/about_the_maemo_summit_2009_and_the_nokia_n900/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2009 21:20:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/about_the_maemo_summit_2009_and_the_nokia_n900/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So I&#39;m back from the 3-day &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.maemo.org/Maemo_Summit_2009&#34;&gt;maemo summit&lt;/a&gt; in Amsterdam.  It was very nice.  Very well organized, and Nokia definitely invested enough in catering, fancy-suited people and such to please all 400 of us.  I met several interesting people, both from the community, as well as Nokia guys.&lt;br /&gt;
The talks were diverse, but interesting (duh?).  I will especially remember the kickoff with its fancy visual effects and loud music that set the mood straight for the entire weekend.&lt;br /&gt;
The best moment was, of course, when it was announced that &lt;strong&gt;every summit participant would receive a n900.  Uncontrolled hapiness all around. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nokia n900 &amp; maemo summit 2009</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/nokia_n900_and_maemo_summit_2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2009 17:40:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/nokia_n900_and_maemo_summit_2009/</guid>
      
      <description>I have been looking for the &#34;perfect mobile companion device&#34; already for a while. Basically I want a &#34;pocket PC that can do as much as possible over which i have as much control as possible so I can do things my way, but still fits in a pocket and which can do gsm and such&#34;
So, something like a netbook, but really portable, and that can also do telephony stuff.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wishlist</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/wishlist/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2009 16:22:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/wishlist/</guid>
      
      <description>I&#39;m starting to keep track of some things I want. I&#39;ve picked Amazon because they have many items in their database.
wishlist</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Froscon 2009 afterthoughts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/froscon_2009_afterthoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2009 19:00:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/froscon_2009_afterthoughts/</guid>
      
      <description></description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arch Linux 2009.08 &amp; Froscon 2009</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/arch_linux_2009.08_and_froscon_2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2009 12:36:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/arch_linux_2009.08_and_froscon_2009/</guid>
      
      <description>So, the Arch Linux 2009.08 release is now behind us, nicely on schedule.
I hope people will like AIF because it was a lot of work and we didn&#39;t receive much feedback. I personally like it to apply my fancy backup restoration approach.
But I&#39;m sure if more people would look at the code we would find quite some design and implementation things that could be improved. (With uzbl I was amazed how much difference it can make if many people all have ideas and opinions about every little detail)</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fosdem 2009</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/fosdem_2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2009 21:20:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/fosdem_2009/</guid>
      
      <description>
I&#39;m particulary interested in:
The out-of-the-box concepts of Exherbo. I hope to see more things like this. Various talks at OpenSuse about distribution development, their build service, etc. tools such as func and puppet. syslinux, upstart, ext4 etc. Some mysql stuff and the filesystem i/o from a db perspective talk. </description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jobhunt over.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/jobhunt_over/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2008 18:07:35 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/jobhunt_over/</guid>
      
      <description>What better way to launch the new year then starting to work as a System Engineer/Developer for a consulting firm where everyone breathes Linux and Open Source?
Next week I&#39;ll start at Kangaroot. Woohoo.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#1 productivity tip: showers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/number_1_productivity_tip_showers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2008 17:43:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/number_1_productivity_tip_showers/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When you&#39;re stuck on a problem, or not even stuck but you just want to boost your creative/out-of-the-box thinking...&lt;br /&gt;
Take a shower.  When I&#39;m thinking about a problem and I take a shower, the ideas and thoughts just start popping up, one after each other, or sometimes even two at the same time.  It&#39;s amazing.  And it works every time.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking for a new job</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/looking_for_a_new_job/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2008 20:30:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/looking_for_a_new_job/</guid>
      
      <description>The adventure at Netlog didn&#39;t work out entirely, so I&#39;m looking for a new challenge!
My new ideal (slightly utopic) job would be:
Conceptual engineering while still being close to the technical side as well, most notably system engineering and development. Innovative: go where no one has gone before. Integrated in the open-source world. (Bonus points for companies where open source is key in their business model) To get a detailed overview of my interests and skills, I refer to:</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Requirements for the perfect GTD tool</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/requirements_for_the_perfect_gtd_tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2008 16:04:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/requirements_for_the_perfect_gtd_tool/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been reading &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Getting_Things_Done&#34;&gt;GTD&lt;/a&gt; lately and it&#39;s absolutely a great and inspiring book.&lt;br /&gt;
Having made my home office space into a real &lt;i&gt;Zen&lt;/i&gt; I want to start implementing GTD in my digital life but it seems very hard to find a good GTD tool that fully implements GTD. (even though there are a lot of tools out there)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most interesting ones (each for different reasons) I&#39;ve looked at so far are &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thinkingrock.com.au/index.php&#34;&gt;Thinkingrock&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rousette.org.uk/projects/&#34;&gt;tracks&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://gna.org/projects/yagtd/&#34;&gt;yagtd&lt;/a&gt; (the latter requiring most work before it does everything I need, but it&#39;s also the most easy to dive into the code base). I&#39;m keeping my eyes open because there are certainly more things to discover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though there are probably no applications out there that can do everything I want, I just wanted to share my feature-wishlist.  These are the requirements I find that a really good tool should comply with:&lt;br /&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows sucks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/windows_sucks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2008 14:22:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/windows_sucks/</guid>
      
      <description>I had to fix a problem at my dad&#39;s company...
&#34;The network was broken.&#34;
It was a NetBEUI network connecting some windows stations - it has been running for years - and now suddenly the nodes couldn&#39;t find eachother.
One of the boxes (windows 2000 iirc) had 2 network cards, one for the network, the other not used for anything (not even connected). Disabling the latter - not even touching the former - fixed half of the network.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I survived LCL 31-3-2008</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/i_survived_lcl_31_3_2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2008 12:10:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/i_survived_lcl_31_3_2008/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On 31-3-2008 &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lcl.be&#34;&gt;LCL&lt;/a&gt;, one of the most used datacenters in Belgium - and the only one with a 0% downtime record in Belgium - had major power issues with their datacenter in Diegem, bringing lots of Belgian parties offline.  (more specifics &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.be/search?q=lcl+diegem+power+failure&#34;&gt;on the net&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re one of the sysadmins of a website with 35M members and 150M hits per day this means you&#39;re in for an exciting night ...</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DDM : a Distributed Data Manager</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ddm_a_distributed_data_manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2008 20:28:16 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ddm_a_distributed_data_manager/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;UPDATE: this information is outdated.  See &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/Dieterbe/ddm/tree/master&#34; title=&#34;http://github.com/Dieterbe/ddm/tree/master&#34;&gt;http://github.com/Dieterbe/ddm/tree/master&lt;/a&gt; for latest information.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have multiple sets of data (e.g.: music, images, documents, movies, ...) and you use these on more then one system ( e.g. a laptop and a file server) then you probably also have some &#39;rules&#39; on how you use these on your systems.  For example after capturing new images you maybe put them on your laptop first but you like to sync them to your file server frequently.  On the other hand you also want all your high-res images (stored on the server) available for editing on the laptop, and to make it more complicated you might have the same images in a smaller format on your server (for gallery programs etc.) and want these (or a select few albums of them) available on the road. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more different types of data you have and the more you have specific work flows the harder it becomes to keep your data as up to date as possible and consistent on your boxes.  You could manually rsync/(s)cp your data but you end up in having a mess (at least that&#39;s how it turned out on my boxes). Putting everything under version control is great for text files and such, but it&#39;s not an option for bigger (binary) files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to keep all my stuff neatly organised in my home directories and I want to create good work flows with as minimum hassle as possible, so I decided to write DDM: the Distributed Data Manager.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m not going to Fosdem 2008</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/im_not_going_to_fosdem_2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2008 20:37:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/im_not_going_to_fosdem_2008/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wish I could put this on my webpage :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fosdem.org&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/files/blog/fosdem/going-to-2008.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;I&#39;m going to FOSDEM, the Free and Open Source Software Developers&#39; European Meeting&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The key to mastering a musical instrument ...</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the_key_to_mastering_a_musical_instrument/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2008 23:36:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the_key_to_mastering_a_musical_instrument/</guid>
      
      <description>The key to mastering a musical instrument is learning an other.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Afgestudeerd - graduated</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/afgestudeerd_graduated/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2007 15:23:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/afgestudeerd_graduated/</guid>
      
      <description>Foreign visitors: yeay I graduated today \o/
Dutchies: joepie, afgestudeerd...
Vandaag proclamatie gehad, ben geslaagd met voldoening, zelfs geen enkele buis \o/
En een 12/20 voor de Masterproef :-)</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thesis finished</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/thesis_finished/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2007 16:55:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/thesis_finished/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, after a night of searching and fixing spelling errors, things that could be better explained and other small details,&lt;br /&gt;
I got my thesis printed and delivered the six books to my school.&lt;br /&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I just became a &#34;System &amp; Network Architect&#34;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/i_just_became_a_system_and_network_architect/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2007 20:11:07 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/i_just_became_a_system_and_network_architect/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just signed my contract at &lt;a href=&#34;http://incrowd.be/&#34;&gt;Incrowd&lt;/a&gt;, the company behind sites such as &lt;a href=&#34;http://redbox.be/&#34;&gt;redbox&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebox.com/&#34;&gt;facebox&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will be working there in a team of all young, enthusiastic people.  Among those, some people are already familiar to me:  my old friend &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lievendekeyser.net/&#34;&gt;Lieven&lt;/a&gt; (we&#39;ve played in a band together but kept in touch afterwards) and my ex-classmate &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jurriaanpersyn.com/&#34;&gt;Jurriaan&lt;/a&gt;.  Both of them love their jobs btw :-).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My official title is &#34;System &amp;amp; Network architect&#34;.&lt;br /&gt;
Things I will be doing there is </description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kwartee 4 2007 verslag</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/kwartee_4_2007_verslag/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2007 12:09:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/kwartee_4_2007_verslag/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dit weekend (17-18 maart) ben ik naar &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.formaat.be/index.php?l1=5&amp;amp;l2=18&amp;amp;l3=19&amp;amp;l4=129&#34;&gt;Kwartee 4&lt;/a&gt; geweest.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.formaat.be/index.php?l1=5&amp;amp;l2=18&amp;amp;l3=19&#34;&gt;Kwartee weekends&lt;/a&gt; worden georganiseerd door &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.formaat.be/&#34;&gt;Formaat&lt;/a&gt; (vroeger bekend als VFJ) en ging door in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.destelheide.be/&#34;&gt;vormingscentrum destelheide&lt;/a&gt; te Dworp (dichtbij Halle, ten zuiden van Brussel).&lt;br /&gt;
Twee man sterk (Steven en ik) vertegenwoordigden we &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jhsjatoo.org/&#34;&gt;jeugdhuis SjaTOo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fosdem 2007 review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/fosdem_2007_review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2007 21:02:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/fosdem_2007_review/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every year, during a special weekend in February, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ulb.ac.be/&#34;&gt;University Libre of Brussels&lt;/a&gt; suddenly becomes a little more geeky.&lt;br /&gt;
It&#39;s that time of the year when many European (and some inter-continental) colleagues join us at&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fosdem.org&#34;&gt;Fosdem: the Free and Open source Software Developers&#39; European Meeting&lt;/a&gt; (more info &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fosdem.org/about/fosdem&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
