<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>web2.0 on Dieter&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/web2.0/</link>
    <description>Recent content in web2.0 on Dieter&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 May 2008 12:39:28 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/web2.0/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the Netlog Developer Pages</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/announcing_the_netlog_developer_pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2008 12:39:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/announcing_the_netlog_developer_pages/</guid>
      
      <description>At work, we&#39;ve setup the Netlog Developer Pages
It is the place where you can/will find all information around our OpenSocial implementation, our own API, skin development, sample code and so on.
We&#39;ve also launched a group where you can communicate with fellow developers and Netlog employees.
The page also features a blog where you can follow what is going on in the Netlog Tech team.
PS: We&#39;ve also updated our jobs page</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Webpages should not contain &#34;add to Digg / Del.icio.us / Technorati /...&#34; links</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/webpages_should_not_contain_add_to_digg_delicious_technorati_links/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2007 12:38:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/webpages_should_not_contain_add_to_digg_delicious_technorati_links/</guid>
      
      <description>I don&#39;t like pages / articles / blog posts /.. accompanied by &#34;Digg this&#34;, &#34;add to Del.icio.us&#34; or &#34;add to Technorati&#34; links.
Why not? Because this is meta level functionality. Not functionality of the blog/article/page in question, but on a higher level. And thus this should be handled on a higher level: the web browser. Just like we can create and manage bookmarks (I mean the old fashioned ones, not the delicious ones) in our browser: this is not the task of a web page.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhpDeliciousClient, a php cli client to administer del.icio.us accounts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/phpdeliciousclient_a_php_cli_client_to_administer_delicious_accounts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2007 16:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/phpdeliciousclient_a_php_cli_client_to_administer_delicious_accounts/</guid>
      
      <description>PhpDeliciousClient is a console based client for doing maintenance on Del.icio.us accounts.
I wrote it because - to my knowledge - there currently is no good program (including the personalized del.icio.us web page itself) that lets you make changes to your del.icio.us data in a powerful, productive manner. (with data I primarily mean tags. Posts and bundles are considered less important).
You probably are familiar with the fact that a Delicious account (or any tag based meta data organizing system, for that matter) can soon become bloated: It gets filled with way too many tags.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhpDeliciousClient</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/php_delicious_client/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2007 13:52:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/php_delicious_client/</guid>
      
      <description>Introduction PhpDeliciousClient is a CLI program for administering your Delicous account. When you invoke it from the command line you have some methods to administer your tags and your posts.
It&#39;s written in PHP and uses Ed Eliot&#39;s PhpDelicous class to contact the del.icio.us api. (included in download)
PhpDeliciousClient is licensed under the GPL v2, while the PhpDelicious class is licensed under the BSD license.
Why? The main reason I started developing it is because administering your account on the del.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting statistics about events that don&#39;t trigger page requests with Google Analytics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/getting_statistics_about_events_that_dont_trigger_page_requests_with_google_analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2007 19:27:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/getting_statistics_about_events_that_dont_trigger_page_requests_with_google_analytics/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You probably already heard of &lt;a href=&#34;www.google.com/analytics&#34;&gt;Google Analytics&lt;/a&gt;.  It&#39;s a pretty nice program that (&lt;em&gt;basically&lt;/em&gt;) gathers data about visits of your site and creates reports of it.  It works by including some JavaScript code on your page, so that each page request triggers a call to the Analytics tracker sending along some data such as which page is requested and which resolution was used. (no personal or other privacy-sensitive data is sent).  But here is the deal!  I just discovered that you can also track &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/support/googleanalytics/bin/answer.py?answer=55597&amp;amp;topic=11012&#34;&gt;events that don&#39;t require page requests!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Think of links to files or to external locations, JavaScript events (Ajax anyone?) or even Flash events (but who is crazy enough to use Flash anyway?).</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bye, Google sandbox!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/bye_google_sandbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2007 12:01:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/bye_google_sandbox/</guid>
      
      <description>Today I&#39;m finally out of Google&#39;s Sandbox.
Google has this system called the sandbox where new pages go into for 6 months, in order to prevent scammers/spammers from resurrecting dummy pages - and scoring well in Google - all the time.
During these 6 months a page will score very bad in search results, even if it should rate very well for the specific keywords.
Smart people will look at my first post, dated 03/04/2007, but keep in mind that before this blog existed I already had a dummy page with my name on (the keywords I want to score on) as soon as I could because back then I already knew I wanted to put a blog here and I wanted to get out of the sandbox as soon as possible.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Figuring out CakePHP&#39;s new AuthComponent</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/figuring_out_cakephp_new_authcomponent/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2007 15:52:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/figuring_out_cakephp_new_authcomponent/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the Cake community, there has always been much interest in authentication/authorization systems.  The issue of authentication has been addressed in several add-ons provided by the community, such as &lt;a href=&#34;http://bakery.cakephp.org/articles/view/147&#34;&gt;DAuth&lt;/a&gt; (written by me), &lt;a href=&#34;http://bakery.cakephp.org/articles/view/99&#34;&gt;OthAuth&lt;/a&gt; (written by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.devmoz.com/blog&#34;&gt;Crazylegs&lt;/a&gt;) and &lt;a href=&#34;http://bakery.cakephp.org/tags/view/auth&#34;&gt;many others&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, one of the additions to the 1.2 branch which is currently in active development , is a built-in auth module.  A module that isn&#39;t finished yet but it sure is worth it looking at.  (In fact I&#39;m thinking about making a new dAuth version built on cake&#39;s own auth system.).  As most bakers know, there is very little information about the 1.2 branch in general, and the auth component in specific.  So what I will try to do, is delve in the code, mess with it, and explain my findings in this post.  </description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fosdem 2007 review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/fosdem_2007_review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2007 21:02:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/fosdem_2007_review/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every year, during a special weekend in February, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ulb.ac.be/&#34;&gt;University Libre of Brussels&lt;/a&gt; suddenly becomes a little more geeky.&lt;br /&gt;
It&#39;s that time of the year when many European (and some inter-continental) colleagues join us at&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fosdem.org&#34;&gt;Fosdem: the Free and Open source Software Developers&#39; European Meeting&lt;/a&gt; (more info &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fosdem.org/about/fosdem&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello world!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/blogpost1_hello_world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2007 14:45:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/blogpost1_hello_world/</guid>
      
      <description>Finally, my own website...
I already wanted to get this up for a long time. My initial idea was writing (and styling) it all from scratch using the marvelous CakePHP framework along with an authentication system i wrote, dAuth.
However, due to my lack of time I decided to use the excellent drupal platform, of which I&#39;m quite sure will get the job done equally well, while drastically liberating my time, so I can invest it in other projects :-)</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
