<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>arch on Dieter&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/arch/</link>
    <description>Recent content in arch on Dieter&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2013 14:46:32 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/arch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pixie: simple photo management using directory layouts and tags.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/pixie/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2013 14:46:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/pixie/</guid>
      
      <description>So you have a few devices with pictures, and maybe some additional pictures your friends sent you.  You have a lot of pictures of the same thing and probably too high of a resolution.  Some may require some editing.  How do you easily create photo albums out of this mess?  And how do you do it in a way
that keeps a simple and elegant, yet flexible file/directory layout for portability and simplicity?
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resigning as Arch Linux developer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/resigning_arch_linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2012 16:50:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/resigning_arch_linux/</guid>
      
      <description>A few days ago, I resigned as Arch Linux developer. I&#39;m sad to go, but I felt like my work on Arch became a drag, so it was time I officialized my decreased interest. The Releng team we started more than 3 years ago is now dead, but other developers are showing interest in iso building and installer scripts, so as long as they don&#39;t burn out, you&#39;ll see new isos again.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lighttpd socket Arch Linux /var/run tmpfs tmpfiles.d</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/lighttpd-socket-arch-linux-var-run-tmpfs-tmpfiles.d/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2012 23:05:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/lighttpd-socket-arch-linux-var-run-tmpfs-tmpfiles.d/</guid>
      
      <description>On Arch Linux, and probably many other distros /run is a new tmpfs, and /var/run symlinks to it. With Lighttpd you might have a fastcgi socket defined something like &#34;/var/run/lighttpd/sockets/mywebsite.sock&#34;. This won&#39;t work anymore as after each reboot /var/run is an empty directory and lighttpd won&#39;t start, /var/log/lighttpd/error.log will tell you: 2012-03-16 09:21:34: (log.c.166) server started 2012-03-16 09:21:34: (mod_fastcgi.c.977) bind failed for: unix:/var/run/lighttpd/sockets/mywebsite.sock-0 No such file or directory 2012-03-16 09:21:34: (mod_fastcgi.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where are the new Arch Linux release images?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/where_are_the_new_arch_linux_images/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2011 21:29:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/where_are_the_new_arch_linux_images/</guid>
      
      <description></description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can we build a simple, cross-distribution installation framework?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/can_we_build_a_simple_cross-distribution_installation_framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2011 23:46:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/can_we_build_a_simple_cross-distribution_installation_framework/</guid>
      
      <description>Today at Fosdem 2011 I did my talk Can we build a simple, cross-distribution installation framework? Basically, using the Arch Installation Framework as a starting point, along with the notion that most of the code is actually not Arch-specific I adressed other distros to check if there was any interest in sharing workload on the distribution-agnostic aspects of the framework. If other distros with a similar philosophy of little-abstractions/KISS would join, we would all reap the benefits of a simple, yet quite featureful installer.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Filesystem code in AIF</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/filesystem_code_in_aif/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2010 12:24:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/filesystem_code_in_aif/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In light of the work and discussions around supporting Nilfs2 and Btrfs on Arch Linux and its installer AIF,&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;ve shared some &lt;a href=&#34;http://mailman.archlinux.org/pipermail/arch-releng/2010-December/001310.html&#34;&gt;AIF filesystem code design insights and experiences&lt;/a&gt; on the arch-releng mailing list.&lt;br /&gt;
This is some hard to understand code.  Partly because it&#39;s in bash (and I&#39;ve needed to work around some limitations in bash),&lt;br /&gt;
partly because there is some complex logic going on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it&#39;s very useful material for those who are interested (it can also help understanding the user aspect),&lt;br /&gt;
so I wanted to share an improved version here.&lt;br /&gt;
On a related topic: I proposed to do a session at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fosdem.org&#34;&gt;Fosdem 2011/&#34;distro miniconf&#34;&lt;/a&gt; about simple (console based) installers for Linux,&lt;br /&gt;
and how multiple distributions could share efforts maintaining installation tools, because there are a lot of cross-distribution concerns&lt;br /&gt;
which are not trivial to get right (mostly filesystems, but I also think about clock adjustments, bootloaders, etc).&lt;br /&gt;
Already several distro&#39;s use the (or a fork of) the Arch installer, for example &lt;a href=&#34;http://pentoo.blogspot.com/2010/10/pentoo-installation-made-easy.html&#34;&gt;Pentoo&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;br /&gt;
but I think cooperation could be much better and more efficient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway:&lt;br /&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>the &#34;Community Contributions&#34; section on the Arch Linux forums is a goldmine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the_community_contributions_section_on_the_arch_linux_forums_is_a_goldmine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2010 22:11:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the_community_contributions_section_on_the_arch_linux_forums_is_a_goldmine/</guid>
      
      <description>The Community contributions subforum of the Arch Linux forums is awesome.
It is the birthplace of many applications, most of them not Arch Linux specific.
File managers, media players, browsers, window managers, text editors, todo managers, and so on. Many shell scripts, urxvt extensions and dwm patches aswell.
Most of the apps are designed after suckless/KISS principles, but there are also some GUI programs.
If you like to discover new apps and tools, check it out.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back from Canada, Archcon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/back_from_canada_archcon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2010 23:10:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/back_from_canada_archcon/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m back from Canada/Archcon, and it was great. I&#39;ve been in Toronto for 11 days, and visited Montreal for 3 days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Archcon&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Archcon was small (20-ish people).  (That&#39;s what you get for doing it in Canada ;), but very nice.&lt;br /&gt;
Interesting talks, informal, good vibe, decent logistics and catering.&lt;br /&gt;
This year it happened because Dusty and Ricardo actually just wanted to have a conference without worrying too much about the attendance,&lt;br /&gt;
next year we should do it again because Arch (conferences) rock(s), and because we need more visitors.  More central locations such as Seattle and Europe have been suggested.&lt;br /&gt;
Either way, next year both Judd (founder) and Aaron (current overlord) should be there. (this year they both had lame excuses like family reunions and &#34;almost getting married&#34;.  Congrats btw, Aaron!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was an absolute pleasure to meet some more of my fellow devs, and users.&lt;br /&gt;
Here is a pic from the group (unfortunately, a few are missing)</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Off to Toronto July 14-28, Archcon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/off_to_toronto_july_14-28_archcon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2010 11:34:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/off_to_toronto_july_14-28_archcon/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As mentioned &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/uzbl_monitoring_aif_talks&#34;&gt;earlier&lt;/a&gt;, I&#39;ll be at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.archlinux.ca/archcon2010/&#34;&gt;Archcon in Toronto&lt;/a&gt; in a few weeks.&lt;br /&gt;
It&#39;s a very small conference, and the first of its kind.  At the &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/froscon_2009_afterthoughts&#34;&gt;last FrOSCon&lt;/a&gt; we have been playing with the idea to hold an informal Arch conference in Europe, but those were just ideas.  Dusty and Ricardo beat us with an actual implementation.&lt;br /&gt;
This is great, and one of the milestones in Arch Linux history.  Which is why I want to be there and help making it better.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uzbl, monitoring, AIF talks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/uzbl_monitoring_aif_talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2010 12:06:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/uzbl_monitoring_aif_talks/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently did two talks, for which the videos are now online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uzbl.org/news.php?id=25&#34;&gt;Uzbl lightningtalk @ fosdem 2010&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open Source Monitoring tools lightning talk @ &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kangaroot-showcase.be/&#34;&gt;Kangaroot showcase&lt;/a&gt; 2009.  This one is password protected.  If you were a participant, you should have received the pass&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If all goes well, I&#39;ll be at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.archlinux.ca/archcon2010/&#34;&gt;ArchCon&lt;/a&gt; this summer, where I&#39;ll be doing these talks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.archlinux.ca/archcon2010/?p=67&#34;&gt;AIF: The Arch Installation Framework&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.archlinux.ca/archcon2010/?p=73&#34;&gt;Uzbl &amp; web interface tools which adhere to the unix philosophy&lt;/a&gt;. Whereas in the fosdem talk I had to focus a lot of information into a short timeslot, here I&#39;ll elaborate a bit more&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;re not sure yet if those talks will get videotaped.&lt;br /&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fosdem 2010</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/fosdem_2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2010 17:10:16 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/fosdem_2010/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ll be at fosdem - 10th edition - again this year.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fosdem.org&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/files/blog/fosdem/going-to-2010.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;I&#39;m going to FOSDEM, the Free and Open Source Software Developers&#39; European Meeting&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ll be presenting a &lt;a href=&#34;http://fosdem.org/2010/schedule/events/uzbl&#34;&gt;lightning talk&lt;/a&gt; about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uzbl.org/&#34;&gt;uzbl&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
Also, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.archlinux.org/&#34;&gt;Arch Linux&lt;/a&gt; guys Roman, JGC, Thomas and me will hang out at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://fosdem.org/2010/schedule/devrooms/distributions&#34;&gt;distro miniconf&lt;/a&gt;.  We might join the &lt;a href=&#34;http://fosdem.org/2010/schedule/events/dist_infrastructure&#34;&gt;infrastructure round-table&lt;/a&gt; panel, but there is no concrete information yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More stuff I&#39;m looking forward to:</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arch Linux interview and Uzbl article</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/arch_linux_interview_and_uzbl_article/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2010 21:30:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/arch_linux_interview_and_uzbl_article/</guid>
      
      <description>Arch Linux team interview @ OSNews Uzbl @ LWN.net Apologies for only informing you about the second article now. I assumed most of you follow LWN (you probably should) or found the article anyway.
Of all the articles written about uzbl, no one came close to the quality of Koens work. So even though it&#39;s a bit dated it&#39;s still worth a read.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Froscon 2009 afterthoughts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/froscon_2009_afterthoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2009 19:00:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/froscon_2009_afterthoughts/</guid>
      
      <description></description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arch Linux 2009.08 &amp; Froscon 2009</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/arch_linux_2009.08_and_froscon_2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2009 12:36:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/arch_linux_2009.08_and_froscon_2009/</guid>
      
      <description>So, the Arch Linux 2009.08 release is now behind us, nicely on schedule.
I hope people will like AIF because it was a lot of work and we didn&#39;t receive much feedback. I personally like it to apply my fancy backup restoration approach.
But I&#39;m sure if more people would look at the code we would find quite some design and implementation things that could be improved. (With uzbl I was amazed how much difference it can make if many people all have ideas and opinions about every little detail)</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AIF automatic lvm/dm_crypt installations and test suite</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/aif_automatic_lvm_dm_crypt_installations_and_test_suite/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2009 22:36:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/aif_automatic_lvm_dm_crypt_installations_and_test_suite/</guid>
      
      <description>We&#39;re working hard on a new Arch release. (should be done by froscon)
Amongst the slew of fixes and improvements there are also some cool new things I&#39;m working on.
First of all, I worked more on the automatic installations. Now you can easily install an LVM based Arch system on top of dm_crypt for example.
You type this command:
aif -p automatic -c /usr/share/aif/examples/fancy-install-on-sdaAnd bam you have a complete working system with LVM, dm_crypt etc all set up.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic installations with AIF</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/automatic_installations_with_aif/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2009 13:15:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/automatic_installations_with_aif/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I finished the first working version of AIF&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/Dieterbe/aif/blob/b6aad22d8c0657d9205314b176e31878ffbc46a4/src/core/procedures/automatic&#34;&gt;automatic procedure&lt;/a&gt;, along with a &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/Dieterbe/aif/blob/b6aad22d8c0657d9205314b176e31878ffbc46a4/examples/generic-install-on-sda&#34;&gt;sample config for a basic install.&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me personally this means I can start working on the next step towards my goal of having all my systems &#34;metadata&#34; centrally stored (along with my real &#34;data&#34;), and the possibility to reconstruct all my systems in a deployment-meets-backup-restore fashion ( see &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/rethinking_the_backup_paradigm_a_higher-level_approach&#34; title=&#34;/rethinking_the_backup_paradigm_a_higher-level_approach&#34;&gt;rethinking_the_backup_paradigm_a_higher-level...&lt;/a&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arch Linux release engineering</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/arch_linux_release_engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2009 23:11:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/arch_linux_release_engineering/</guid>
      
      <description>I don&#39;t think I&#39;ve ever seen so much anxiety/impatience/hope/buzz for a new Arch Linux release. (this is because of 2.6.28 with ext4 support).
The last release was 6 months ago, which is not so good.. also the arch-installer project has been slacking for a while. But the Arch devs have been very busy and many things going on. You know how it goes...
That&#39;s why some new people have stepped up to help out on a new release:</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>new AIF release</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/new_aif_release/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2008 09:50:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/new_aif_release/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My holidays present for Arch devs and users: AIF alpha-0.6 !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* Changes since alpha 0.5:</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AIF: the brand new Arch Linux Installation Framework</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/aif_the_brand_new_arch_linux_installation_framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2008 11:45:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/aif_the_brand_new_arch_linux_installation_framework/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I started thinking about writing my own automatic installer that would set up my system exactly the way I want.&lt;br /&gt;
(See &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/rethinking_the_backup_paradigm_a_higher-level_approach&#34; title=&#34;/rethinking_the_backup_paradigm_a_higher-level_approach&#34;&gt;rethinking_the_backup_paradigm_a_higher-level...&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I looked at the official Arch install scripts to see if I could reuse parts of their code, but unfortunately the code was just one big chunk of bash code with the main program and &#34;flow control&#34; (you must first do this step, then that), UI-code (dialogs etc) and backend logic (create filesystems, ...) all mangled up and mixed very closely together.&lt;br /&gt;
Functionality-wise the installer works fine, but I guess the code behind it is the result of years of adding features and quick fixes without refactoring, making it impossible to reuse any of the code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I started to write &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/Dieterbe/aif/&#34;&gt;AIF: the Arch Linux Installation Framework&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
