<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>real life on Dieter&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/real-life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in real life on Dieter&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2007 18:28:17 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/real-life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Video of me drumming</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/video_of_me_drumming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2007 18:28:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/video_of_me_drumming/</guid>
      
      <description>I recorded a little drumvideo while practicing.
It&#39;s just some improvisation... Find the mistakes! ;-)
Recorded with 2 shure SM57&#39;s, an M-audio mobilepre USB and the iSight cam in my macbook pro.
The mic setup had to be close enough to sound direct and focused without too much reverb, and still far enough to allow all instruments too come through. After some experimenting I decided to place the mics behind the kit, next to me ( one each side), just below the height of the hips.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Masterproef</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/masterproef/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2007 16:01:07 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/masterproef/</guid>
      
      <description> Op deze pagina verschijnen enkele gegevens, documenten en toevoegingen in het algemeen in het kader van mijn masterproef. (ook wel bekend als eindwerk of thesis).
Titel (nl): Geautomatiseerde webwinkel en orderverwerking Title (en): Automated webstore and order processing School: Katholieke Hogeschool Sint - Lieven Abstract (nl + en) Poster (en) Paper (en, 5 blz) Scriptie (nl, 79 blz) Presentatie proefverdediging (niet de echte verdediging) (nl, 23 slides) Presentatie verdediging (nl, 25 slides) </description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
