<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Openstack on Dieter&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/openstack/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Openstack on Dieter&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 May 2012 11:50:11 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/openstack/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Dell crowbar openstack swift</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/dell_crowbar_openstack_swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2012 11:50:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/dell_crowbar_openstack_swift/</guid>
      <description>Learned about &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dellcloudedge/crowbar&#34;&gt;Dell Crowbar&lt;/a&gt; the other day.  It seems to be (becoming) a tool I&#39;ve wanted for quite a while, because it takes automating physical infrastructure to a new level, and is also convenient on virtual.

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

It provides a central management interface which leverages chef, but extends it to a broader scope: it takes care of configuring the bios and raid firmware, BMC/IPMI, doing a PXE autoinstall and setting up chef, which of course does everything else you might need.

&lt;br/&gt;The crowbar admin machine also runs Nagios and Ganglia and the configuration is automatically kept in sync with the roles you apply to your nodes. (adding support for a different monitoring/alerting solution is probably not too hard.  I&#39;m thinking about graphite support or even integrating with an existing graphite setup)

&lt;br/&gt;It uses a plugin system called barclamps and it&#39;s vendor-agnostic.  (minus the barclamps that deal with your hardware)

It can even suggest roles for your nodes based on best practices (like: for an X-node openstack cluster we recommend Y proxy&#39;s and Z foobars) and hardware properties it discovers (storage vs cpu power vs ram etc)

&lt;br/&gt;Next step would be automating purchase orders, delivery handling and physical installation in racks.

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this tool deserves more attention and should be added to your devops toolchain for the cloud (&lt;i&gt;triple buzzword bonus!!!&lt;/i&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

I&#39;ve currently been using it to easily setup an &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dellcloudedge/crowbar/wiki/Swift--barclamp&#34;&gt;openstack swift&lt;/a&gt; test cluster on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dellcloudedge/crowbar/wiki/Running-Crowbar-in-VirtualBox-VMs&#34;&gt;a virtualbox infrastructure&lt;/a&gt; (even the latter is easily automated with a shell script), and I&#39;m looking forward to use it on physical hardware and have it take care of the bios and raid settings, I&#39;m expecting it will even set the LCD&#39;s on the frontpanel to something interesting automatically. (btw the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dell.com/poweredge&#34;&gt;12G poweredge servers&lt;/a&gt; have some neat new features)

&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>