<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vimeo on Dieter Plaetinck&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/vimeo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vimeo on Dieter Plaetinck&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2013 12:46:32 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/vimeo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Vimeo holiday special &amp; other great videos</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/vimeo_holiday_special_and_other_great_videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2013 12:46:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/vimeo_holiday_special_and_other_great_videos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;

We (the &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/staff&#34;&gt;Vimeo Staff&lt;/a&gt;) just &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/blog/post:602&#34;&gt;released&lt;/a&gt; the &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/82236972&#34;&gt;2013 Vimeo Holiday Special&lt;/a&gt;, embedded below.

&lt;br/&gt;(and I have a line in it! &#34;Who&#39;s behind this?&#34;)

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&#34;//player.vimeo.com/video/82236972?title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&amp;amp;color=33a352&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;211&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;



&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Here&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/55646323&#34;&gt;last year&#39;s Holiday video&lt;/a&gt; which is just as cool.

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

Not a lot of people know this but we actually produce a bunch of our own videos.

&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;

Some of my favorites include &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/3718294&#34;&gt;Auto-tuning&lt;/a&gt;,

&lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/5425957&#34;&gt;Idea&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/53026635&#34;&gt;Vimeo goes bowling&lt;/a&gt;,

&lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/46701971&#34;&gt;Vimeo production reel 2012&lt;/a&gt;,

&lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/35514005&#34;&gt;Open your eyes to the new vimeo&lt;/a&gt; and

&lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/7100569&#34;&gt;Brad!&lt;/a&gt;.

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

While I&#39;m at it...

Over the last 2 years I&#39;ve discovered many great videos from our diverse user base through staff screenings and by just browsing around.

I&#39;ve narrowed it down to this list of all-time favorites:

&lt;br&gt;

&lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/59956490&#34;&gt;To this day&lt;/a&gt;,

&lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/43005056&#34;&gt;The Art of Making, Alma Flamenca&lt;/a&gt;,

&lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/79010983&#34;&gt;Record Breaker&lt;/a&gt;,

&lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/56433514&#34;&gt;Malaria&lt;/a&gt;,

&lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/43800150&#34;&gt;Portal: Terminal velocity (must-see for all half-life/portal fans)&lt;/a&gt;,

&lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/24456787&#34;&gt;The arctic light&lt;/a&gt;,

&lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/36100188&#34;&gt;iPhone 4s // Thailand&lt;/a&gt;,

&lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/42619545&#34;&gt;Ending Overfishing&lt;/a&gt;.

&lt;br/&gt;

I hope you have some time to check out this amazing content! (protip: watch later button &amp; couch mode / smart tv vimeo app)

&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving to New York City</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/moving-to-nyc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2012 16:50:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/moving-to-nyc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;

I have a one-way ticket to NYC on Sept. 21st.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/about&#34;&gt;Vimeo HQ&lt;/a&gt; is in Manhattan, and practically the whole team works in the building so it makes sense for me to relocate and join them locally.

I&#39;m looking forward to working with the colleagues face to face, but mainly I&#39;m looking forward to the experience of living in such a different place, and exploring the US.

In fact, I already have some small trips planned (Hamptons NY, camping in Pennsylvania, skiing in New York this winter) with some friends &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/thailand_berlin_velocity_nyc_ghent_metal.html&#34;&gt;I met last year in NY&lt;/a&gt;.

We&#39;re also looking into possibly going to California or Mexico for the holidays.

&lt;br/&gt;

I&#39;ve been living in &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ghent&#34;&gt;Ghent&lt;/a&gt; for about a year now and absolutely loved it.  I&#39;ll definitely miss Ghent, I think NYC might be a bit too hectic for my taste, but I just &lt;i&gt;have&lt;/i&gt; to try this and see :)  There&#39;s so much to learn and explore.

I especially have high expectations of the music scene, which I&#39;ld like to get involved in. (btw my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lightbulbinferno.com/&#34;&gt;ex-band&lt;/a&gt; is recording an EP and looking for a new drummer)

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;35%&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/files/travel_documents_nyc.jpg&#34;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

As for things in Belgium: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.10151066748715279.458359.627030278&amp;type=3&amp;l=1fa8adec26&#34;&gt;selling furniture&lt;/a&gt;, moving out of my apartment next weekend, having a goodbye drink friday sept. 14th, flying a week later and returning in the summer 2013 for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gentsefeesten.be/&#34;&gt;gentse feesten&lt;/a&gt;.  Maybe I&#39;ll visit sooner, depending on how homesick I get :)

&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joining Vimeo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/joining_vimeo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2012 11:50:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/joining_vimeo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Working on &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/building_a_search_engine.html&#34;&gt;scalable information retrieval systems at the university of Ghent&lt;/a&gt; has been very fun: interesting and challenging work, smart team, and an environment that fosters growth and innovation.  I could definitely see myself continuing there&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/&#34;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt; got in touch and told me about their plans&amp;hellip; specifically what&amp;rsquo;s going into the &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/35514005&#34;&gt;new version&lt;/a&gt; and what other stuff they have on their roadmap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can honestly say vimeo is the most beautiful web property I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen [*], not just that, they also provide a top product/service, and host a great community of passionate people who create some of the most beautiful online videos I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen.  (examples: &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/37071868&#34;&gt;Vietnam travel report&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/33993701&#34;&gt;Sabian cymbals taking advertising to a whole new level in this video with my musician hero Mike Portnoy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/23237102&#34;&gt;a city time lapse video&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From what I can tell, they also do product management well:  they know what their territory is, and how to cultivate it through &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/16929813&#34;&gt;stellar community management&lt;/a&gt;.  They are &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/21585295&#34;&gt;not a general purpose video site and hence do not compete directly with YouTube or Facebook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now, I have the opportunity to be a part of that.  After much pondering I decided to go for it.  Resigning at the university was hard but smooth, I felt I had to take this chance and they were very supportive.

&lt;br/&gt;I&#39;ll be working on the infrastructure/backend side of things, I&#39;m actually working on transcoding infrastructure right now.  Working from my place in Ghent, a move to NYC at some point in the future might happen, but we&#39;ll see...

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

[*] When they told me the new version would be more appealing than the old, I couldn&#39;t believe that&#39;s possible.

but to my own surprise they succeeded.

&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>