<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>python on Dieter&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in python on Dieter&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2011 22:32:12 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Poor mans pickle implementations benchmark</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/poor_mans_pickle_implementations_benchmark/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2011 22:32:12 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/poor_mans_pickle_implementations_benchmark/</guid>
      
      <description></description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dvcs-autosync: An open source dropbox clone... well.. almost</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/dvcs-autosync_an_opensource_dropbox_clone_well_almost/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2011 21:48:56 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/dvcs-autosync_an_opensource_dropbox_clone_well_almost/</guid>
      
      <description>I found the Dvcs-autosync project on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://lists.madduck.net/listinfo/vcs-home&#34;&gt;vcs-home&lt;/a&gt; mailing list,
which btw is a great list for folks who are doing stuff like maintaining their home directory in a vcs.
&lt;br/&gt;In short:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;simple python tool (600 sloc), works with your dvcs of choice (mainly tested/used with git)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;watches for inotify events, performs commits on changes (coalesces some changes together)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;synchronizes with other clones (remotes), uses xmpp for push notifications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;let&#39;s you know what&#39;s going on through libnotify popups or whatever&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mayrhofer.eu.org/dvcs-autosync&#34;&gt;home page: http://mayrhofer.eu.org/dvcs-autosync&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://gitorious.org/dvcs-autosync/dvcs-autosync&#34;&gt;dvcs-autosync gitorious repo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://lists.madduck.net/pipermail/vcs-home/2011-March/000314.html&#34;&gt;initial announcement on vcs-home&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
Use cases:
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating blogs from Drupal to Pyblosxom</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/migrating_blogs_from_drupal_to_pyblosxom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2010 19:54:07 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/migrating_blogs_from_drupal_to_pyblosxom/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://pyblosxom.bluesock.org/&#34;&gt;pyblosxom&lt;/a&gt; is a pretty cool blogging platform written in python.&lt;br /&gt;
Like many of the modern minimal blog engines it works with plaintext files only (no database), has a relatively small codebase, supports many plugins (like markdown support), is written in a proper scripting language, has a simple and clean file structure, is seo-friendly, and so on.&lt;br /&gt;
The one feature that sets it apart from other minimal blog engines is that it supports comments, and doesn&#39;t just rely on an external service like disqus, but stores comments as plaintext files as well.&lt;br /&gt;
Some features seem a bit overengineered (like, multiple possible locations to store themes (known as &#34;flavours&#34;) and templates; I&#39;m a fan of convention over configuration and keeping things simple), but discussing this with the maintainer revealed this is because pyblosxom is meant as a reimplementation of the original perl-based bloxsom project.  Over time features could be simplified and/or redesigned.&lt;br /&gt;
So I plan to migrate this blog from drupal to pyblosxom.&lt;br /&gt;
To do this, I&#39;m building the tool &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Dieterbe/drupal-to-pyblosxom&#34;&gt;drupal-to-pyblosxom&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
The goal is to convert posts, associated metadata (publish time, tags) and comments from the drupal database to pyblosxom files.  Source code display should be converted too (merely a matter of converting between different plugin conventions), and images shown should be downloaded.  Currently I&#39;m about halfway, if there&#39;s anyone out there with a similar use case, help is welcome ;)</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An rss2email fork that sucks less</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/an_rss2email_fork_that_sucks_less/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2010 20:33:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/an_rss2email_fork_that_sucks_less/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.allthingsrss.com/rss2email/&#34;&gt;Rss2email&lt;/a&gt; is a great tool.  I like getting all my news messages in my mailbox and using smtp to make the &#34;news delivery&#34; process more robust makes sense.&lt;br /&gt;
However, there are some things I didn&#39;t like about it so I made a &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/Dieterbe/rss2email/&#34;&gt;github repo&lt;/a&gt; where I maintain an alternative version which (imho) contains several useful improvements, both for end users and for developers/downstreams.&lt;br /&gt;
Also, this was a nice opportunity for me to improve my python skills :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is how it compares:&lt;br /&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of &#34;Python 3 Object Oriented Programming&#34;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/review_of_python_3_object_oriented_programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2010 19:01:09 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/review_of_python_3_object_oriented_programming/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://archlinux.me/dusty/&#34;&gt;Dusty Phillips&lt;/a&gt;, Arch Linux shwag guy, Archcon co-organizer, (python) consultant and since recently &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/back_from_canada_archcon&#34;&gt;buddy of mine&lt;/a&gt; wrote his first &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.packtpub.com/python-3-object-oriented-programming/book?utm_source=dieter.plaetinck.be&amp;amp;utm_medium=bookrev&amp;amp;utm_content=blog&amp;amp;utm_campaign=mdb_004281&#34;&gt;book: Python 3 Object Oriented Programming&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got the opportunity to get a free pdf copy in exchange for a review on my blog, so here we go.&lt;br /&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
