<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>productivity on Dieter&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/productivity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in productivity on Dieter&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2008 17:43:02 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/productivity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>#1 productivity tip: showers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/number_1_productivity_tip_showers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2008 17:43:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/number_1_productivity_tip_showers/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When you&#39;re stuck on a problem, or not even stuck but you just want to boost your creative/out-of-the-box thinking...&lt;br /&gt;
Take a shower.  When I&#39;m thinking about a problem and I take a shower, the ideas and thoughts just start popping up, one after each other, or sometimes even two at the same time.  It&#39;s amazing.  And it works every time.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A fast way to get stuff out of your head and into your GTD inbox</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/a_fast_way_to_get_stuff_out_of_your_head_and_into_your_gtd_inbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2008 20:42:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/a_fast_way_to_get_stuff_out_of_your_head_and_into_your_gtd_inbox/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Often while you&#39;re occupied with something, some thought pops into your head.  Something that you want to remember/do something about.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Requirements for the perfect GTD tool</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/requirements_for_the_perfect_gtd_tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2008 16:04:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/requirements_for_the_perfect_gtd_tool/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been reading &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Getting_Things_Done&#34;&gt;GTD&lt;/a&gt; lately and it&#39;s absolutely a great and inspiring book.&lt;br /&gt;
Having made my home office space into a real &lt;i&gt;Zen&lt;/i&gt; I want to start implementing GTD in my digital life but it seems very hard to find a good GTD tool that fully implements GTD. (even though there are a lot of tools out there)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most interesting ones (each for different reasons) I&#39;ve looked at so far are &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thinkingrock.com.au/index.php&#34;&gt;Thinkingrock&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rousette.org.uk/projects/&#34;&gt;tracks&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://gna.org/projects/yagtd/&#34;&gt;yagtd&lt;/a&gt; (the latter requiring most work before it does everything I need, but it&#39;s also the most easy to dive into the code base). I&#39;m keeping my eyes open because there are certainly more things to discover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though there are probably no applications out there that can do everything I want, I just wanted to share my feature-wishlist.  These are the requirements I find that a really good tool should comply with:&lt;br /&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dump your azerty and querty because the only keyboard layout that makes sense is Dvorak!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/dump_your_azerty_and_querty_because_the_only_keyboard_layout_that_makes_sense_is_dvorak/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2008 21:20:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/dump_your_azerty_and_querty_because_the_only_keyboard_layout_that_makes_sense_is_dvorak/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For a while now I am typing using solely the Dvorak keyboard layout.  I roughly estimate it has been 4 or 5 months now - with the first month being a pain in the ass because i had to relearn typing pretty much from scratch - but now my typing speed is starting to exceed what it used to be in querty, and I still have much headroom to improve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those who have no clue what I&#39;m talking about: think for 30 seconds which characters you type the most and which the least (eg: which characters occur the most/least in the language you type?).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok you got them?  Now look at your keyboard and spot where these characters are.  Now consider where your fingers are most of the time (if you&#39;ve never learned to type: the &#39;base position&#39; for your fingers is on the middle row).  Notice anything strange?</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Per-directory bash history</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/per_directory_bash_history/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2008 21:37:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/per_directory_bash_history/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been thinking about how a specific bash history for each directory could improve productivity, and unlike what I feared it was actually pretty easy to find a solution on the net.
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My favorite bash tricks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my_favorite_bash_tricks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2007 23:38:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my_favorite_bash_tricks/</guid>
      
      <description>Hello everyone.
This post is about bash, the shell providing so many users easy access to the underlying power of their system.
(not bash the quote database, although i really like that website too ;-) )
Most people know the basics, but getting to know it better can really increase your productivity. And when that happens, you might start loving bash as much as I do ;-)
I assume you have a basic knowledge of bash, the history mechanism, and ~/.</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
