<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>php on Dieter&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/php/</link>
    <description>Recent content in php on Dieter&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2010 23:25:46 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/php/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>facebook usrbincrash php implementation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/facebook_usrbincrash_php_implementation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2010 23:25:46 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/facebook_usrbincrash_php_implementation/</guid>
      
      <description>Implementation for Facebook usr bin crash puzzle. (how/why)
I haven&#39;t touched the code for a few months, but better to put it online then to let it rot.
http://github.com/Dieterbe/facebookpuzzles/
2 branches:
master: basically what I submitted to FB, and what just works withpruning: an attempt for futher optimalisation (it only improves the runtime in some cases) but I didn&#39;t finish that version and there&#39;s a bug in it somewhere In the repo you&#39;ll also find various test input files supplied by the community on the forums and a script to benchmark the implementation on all inputfiles.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the Netlog Developer Pages</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/announcing_the_netlog_developer_pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2008 12:39:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/announcing_the_netlog_developer_pages/</guid>
      
      <description>At work, we&#39;ve setup the Netlog Developer Pages
It is the place where you can/will find all information around our OpenSocial implementation, our own API, skin development, sample code and so on.
We&#39;ve also launched a group where you can communicate with fellow developers and Netlog employees.
The page also features a blog where you can follow what is going on in the Netlog Tech team.
PS: We&#39;ve also updated our jobs page</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacking into my router by brute-forcing http authentication</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/hacking_into_my_router_by_brute_force_http_authentication/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2007 22:11:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/hacking_into_my_router_by_brute_force_http_authentication/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I forgot the username and password to access the web panel of my router.&lt;br /&gt;
Luckily I knew some possible usernames and some patterns that I could have used to construct my password, so I just had to try all the combinations... Too much work to do manually but easily done when scripted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the php script that I came up with.  (obviously stripped of my personal stuff).  It got my account in less then a second :)</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bye CakePHP, bye dAuth... Hello Drupal!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/bye_cakephp_bye_dauth_hello_drupal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2007 00:34:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/bye_cakephp_bye_dauth_hello_drupal/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m afraid the time has come to say goodbye to CakePHP, and to the projects I&#39;ve been working on for it.&lt;br /&gt;
I still like Cake ... In fact, the further development of 1.2 goes the more I like it (well, generally spoken that is ... because there are some minor things I don&#39;t like but that&#39;s not important now).  The truth of the matter is I like to develop, I like the php language and I enjoy working with Cake.&lt;br /&gt;
But .. all the sites I currently work on are all community sites or blogs</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dAuth</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/dauth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2007 13:19:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/dauth/</guid>
      
      <description>dAuth is a secure authentication system for CakePHP.
It uses techniques such as the challenge-response paradigm, customizable multiple-stage password hashing, brute force (hammering) detection, session hijacking prevention etc.
Read all about it
You can download the files separately on the before mentioned page or get the tarball that somebody was kind enough to create.
(damn I&#39;m lazy today)
I don&#39;t maintain this any more!</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhpDeliciousClient, a php cli client to administer del.icio.us accounts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/phpdeliciousclient_a_php_cli_client_to_administer_delicious_accounts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2007 16:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/phpdeliciousclient_a_php_cli_client_to_administer_delicious_accounts/</guid>
      
      <description>PhpDeliciousClient is a console based client for doing maintenance on Del.icio.us accounts.
I wrote it because - to my knowledge - there currently is no good program (including the personalized del.icio.us web page itself) that lets you make changes to your del.icio.us data in a powerful, productive manner. (with data I primarily mean tags. Posts and bundles are considered less important).
You probably are familiar with the fact that a Delicious account (or any tag based meta data organizing system, for that matter) can soon become bloated: It gets filled with way too many tags.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhpDeliciousClient</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/php_delicious_client/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2007 13:52:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/php_delicious_client/</guid>
      
      <description>Introduction PhpDeliciousClient is a CLI program for administering your Delicous account. When you invoke it from the command line you have some methods to administer your tags and your posts.
It&#39;s written in PHP and uses Ed Eliot&#39;s PhpDelicous class to contact the del.icio.us api. (included in download)
PhpDeliciousClient is licensed under the GPL v2, while the PhpDelicious class is licensed under the BSD license.
Why? The main reason I started developing it is because administering your account on the del.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drag &#39;n drop tutorial with the CakePHP 1.2 Ajax helper, Prototype framework and Scriptaculous library</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/drag_n_drop_tutorial_with_cakephp_ajax_prototype_scriptaculous/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2007 21:25:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/drag_n_drop_tutorial_with_cakephp_ajax_prototype_scriptaculous/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h3&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the development of my &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/masterproef&#34;&gt;thesis&lt;/a&gt; I wanted to create a drag &#39;n drop interface.  But I never did anything like that, I never used CakePHP&#39;s Ajax helper and neither made I ever use of more advanced functionalities of Scriptaculous/Prototype.  Hell I even never touched Ajax before this! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although there are some basic CakePHP/Ajax tutorials out there, I still had a hard time because some knowledge about Ajax (in CakePHP) was assumed in all of those.  After a lot of googling I even found a tutorial called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dustinweber.com/blog/_archives/2007/4/4/2859177.html&#34;&gt;CakePHP: Sortable AJAX Drag &amp;amp; Drops - The Basics&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;br/&gt;&#34;Perfect!&#34; I thought, until after staring at the article for a long while and I started to notice nowhere in the article &#34;$ajax-&gt;drag&#34;, &#34;$ajax-&gt;drop&#34; or &#34;$ajax-&gt;dropRemote&#34; is used.  (those are calls on the CakePHP Ajax helper to enhance objects to become draggable, or to become a dropbox where draggables can be dropped into).  So the only more or less suited tutorial about drag &#39;n drop was actually about sorting and didn&#39;t use the drag/drop function calls at all.  Even though it contains very useful information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long story short:  I finally got it working (thanks to Krazylegz and kristofer and possibly others too, it has been a while so I may forget someone ;-), and learned a lot in the process.  I will share what I learned with you guys so that hopefully it&#39;s a bit easier for you then what I had to go through.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Figuring out CakePHP&#39;s new AuthComponent</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/figuring_out_cakephp_new_authcomponent/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2007 15:52:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/figuring_out_cakephp_new_authcomponent/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the Cake community, there has always been much interest in authentication/authorization systems.  The issue of authentication has been addressed in several add-ons provided by the community, such as &lt;a href=&#34;http://bakery.cakephp.org/articles/view/147&#34;&gt;DAuth&lt;/a&gt; (written by me), &lt;a href=&#34;http://bakery.cakephp.org/articles/view/99&#34;&gt;OthAuth&lt;/a&gt; (written by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.devmoz.com/blog&#34;&gt;Crazylegs&lt;/a&gt;) and &lt;a href=&#34;http://bakery.cakephp.org/tags/view/auth&#34;&gt;many others&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, one of the additions to the 1.2 branch which is currently in active development , is a built-in auth module.  A module that isn&#39;t finished yet but it sure is worth it looking at.  (In fact I&#39;m thinking about making a new dAuth version built on cake&#39;s own auth system.).  As most bakers know, there is very little information about the 1.2 branch in general, and the auth component in specific.  So what I will try to do, is delve in the code, mess with it, and explain my findings in this post.  </description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fosdem 2007 review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/fosdem_2007_review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2007 21:02:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/fosdem_2007_review/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every year, during a special weekend in February, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ulb.ac.be/&#34;&gt;University Libre of Brussels&lt;/a&gt; suddenly becomes a little more geeky.&lt;br /&gt;
It&#39;s that time of the year when many European (and some inter-continental) colleagues join us at&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fosdem.org&#34;&gt;Fosdem: the Free and Open source Software Developers&#39; European Meeting&lt;/a&gt; (more info &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fosdem.org/about/fosdem&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello world!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/blogpost1_hello_world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2007 14:45:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/blogpost1_hello_world/</guid>
      
      <description>Finally, my own website...
I already wanted to get this up for a long time. My initial idea was writing (and styling) it all from scratch using the marvelous CakePHP framework along with an authentication system i wrote, dAuth.
However, due to my lack of time I decided to use the excellent drupal platform, of which I&#39;m quite sure will get the job done equally well, while drastically liberating my time, so I can invest it in other projects :-)</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
