<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>bash on Dieter&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/bash/</link>
    <description>Recent content in bash on Dieter&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2010 22:59:15 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/bash/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Libui-sh: a library providing UI functions for shell scripts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/libui-sh_a_library_providing_ui_functions_for_shell_scripts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2010 22:59:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/libui-sh_a_library_providing_ui_functions_for_shell_scripts/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
== A library providing UI functions for shell scripts ==&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you write bash/shell scripts, do you write your own error/debug/logging/abort functions?&lt;br /&gt;
Logic that requests the user to input a boolean, string, password, selection out of a list,&lt;br /&gt;
date/time, integer, ... ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Libui-sh is written to take care of all that.&lt;br /&gt;
libui-sh is meant to a be a general-purpose UI abstraction library for shell scripts.&lt;br /&gt;
Low impact, easy to use, but still flexible.&lt;br /&gt;
cli by default, can optionally use ncurses dialogs as well.&lt;br /&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Filesystem code in AIF</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/filesystem_code_in_aif/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2010 12:24:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/filesystem_code_in_aif/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In light of the work and discussions around supporting Nilfs2 and Btrfs on Arch Linux and its installer AIF,&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;ve shared some &lt;a href=&#34;http://mailman.archlinux.org/pipermail/arch-releng/2010-December/001310.html&#34;&gt;AIF filesystem code design insights and experiences&lt;/a&gt; on the arch-releng mailing list.&lt;br /&gt;
This is some hard to understand code.  Partly because it&#39;s in bash (and I&#39;ve needed to work around some limitations in bash),&lt;br /&gt;
partly because there is some complex logic going on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it&#39;s very useful material for those who are interested (it can also help understanding the user aspect),&lt;br /&gt;
so I wanted to share an improved version here.&lt;br /&gt;
On a related topic: I proposed to do a session at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fosdem.org&#34;&gt;Fosdem 2011/&#34;distro miniconf&#34;&lt;/a&gt; about simple (console based) installers for Linux,&lt;br /&gt;
and how multiple distributions could share efforts maintaining installation tools, because there are a lot of cross-distribution concerns&lt;br /&gt;
which are not trivial to get right (mostly filesystems, but I also think about clock adjustments, bootloaders, etc).&lt;br /&gt;
Already several distro&#39;s use the (or a fork of) the Arch installer, for example &lt;a href=&#34;http://pentoo.blogspot.com/2010/10/pentoo-installation-made-easy.html&#34;&gt;Pentoo&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;br /&gt;
but I think cooperation could be much better and more efficient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway:&lt;br /&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A script that pulls photos from facebook</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/a_script_that_pulls_photos_from_facebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2009 17:36:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/a_script_that_pulls_photos_from_facebook/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://fbcmd.dtompkins.com/&#34;&gt;Fbcmd&lt;/a&gt; is pretty cool.&lt;br /&gt;
I quickly hacked this script together which pulls all photo albums from friends on facebook, so I have them available where I want.  (It should also pull your own albums, but I don&#39;t have any so I can&#39;t check that)</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual feedback of the exit status of the previous command in bash</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/visual_feedback_of_the_exit_status_of_the_previous_command_in_bash/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2008 21:56:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/visual_feedback_of_the_exit_status_of_the_previous_command_in_bash/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Put this in your .bashrc, and the current directory in your PS1 will be printed green if the previous command had exit state 0, red otherwise.  No more typing &#39;echo $?&#39;, &#39; &amp;amp;&amp; echo ok&#39;, &#39;|| echo failed&#39; etc on the command line.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DDM v0.4 released</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ddm_v04_released/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2008 16:21:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ddm_v04_released/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;DDM v0.4 has been released.&lt;br /&gt;
Since the last release many, many things have been changed/fixed/added.&lt;br /&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A fast way to get stuff out of your head and into your GTD inbox</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/a_fast_way_to_get_stuff_out_of_your_head_and_into_your_gtd_inbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2008 20:42:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/a_fast_way_to_get_stuff_out_of_your_head_and_into_your_gtd_inbox/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Often while you&#39;re occupied with something, some thought pops into your head.  Something that you want to remember/do something about.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DDM : a Distributed Data Manager</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ddm_a_distributed_data_manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2008 20:28:16 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ddm_a_distributed_data_manager/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;UPDATE: this information is outdated.  See &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/Dieterbe/ddm/tree/master&#34; title=&#34;http://github.com/Dieterbe/ddm/tree/master&#34;&gt;http://github.com/Dieterbe/ddm/tree/master&lt;/a&gt; for latest information.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have multiple sets of data (e.g.: music, images, documents, movies, ...) and you use these on more then one system ( e.g. a laptop and a file server) then you probably also have some &#39;rules&#39; on how you use these on your systems.  For example after capturing new images you maybe put them on your laptop first but you like to sync them to your file server frequently.  On the other hand you also want all your high-res images (stored on the server) available for editing on the laptop, and to make it more complicated you might have the same images in a smaller format on your server (for gallery programs etc.) and want these (or a select few albums of them) available on the road. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more different types of data you have and the more you have specific work flows the harder it becomes to keep your data as up to date as possible and consistent on your boxes.  You could manually rsync/(s)cp your data but you end up in having a mess (at least that&#39;s how it turned out on my boxes). Putting everything under version control is great for text files and such, but it&#39;s not an option for bigger (binary) files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to keep all my stuff neatly organised in my home directories and I want to create good work flows with as minimum hassle as possible, so I decided to write DDM: the Distributed Data Manager.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Per-directory bash history</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/per_directory_bash_history/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2008 21:37:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/per_directory_bash_history/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been thinking about how a specific bash history for each directory could improve productivity, and unlike what I feared it was actually pretty easy to find a solution on the net.
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gtk dialogs for (shell)scripts with zenity and the ask-pass gui tools for ssh-add</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/gtk_dialogs_for_shell_scripts_with_zenity_and_the_ask-pass_gui_tools_for_ssh-add/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2007 18:45:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/gtk_dialogs_for_shell_scripts_with_zenity_and_the_ask-pass_gui_tools_for_ssh-add/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Phew! where to start?  Probably at &lt;a href =&#34;http://www.chimeric.de/blog/2007/1107_mounting_external_truecrypt_volumes_interactively&#34;&gt;this blogpost&lt;/a&gt;.  It&#39;s about making it very easy to work with external encrypted volumes. I&#39;m not going to talk about the article itself but about a great tool i discovered thanks to it: Zenity. </description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emulating two-dimensional (or even multi-dimensional) arrays in bash</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/emulating_two-dimensional_or_even_multi-dimensional_arrays_in_bash/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2007 12:49:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/emulating_two-dimensional_or_even_multi-dimensional_arrays_in_bash/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ever needed to use arrays of two or more dimensions but got stuck on Bash limited array support which provides only 1 dimension?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a trick that let&#39;s you dynamically create variable names.  Using this, you can emulate additional dimensions.&lt;br /&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nagios monitoring in your desktop panel aka Xfce Genmon panel plugin rules!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/nagios_monitoring_in_your_desktop_panel_aka_xfce_genmon_panel_plugin_rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2007 16:42:46 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/nagios_monitoring_in_your_desktop_panel_aka_xfce_genmon_panel_plugin_rules/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;FOSS is written by users, for users, and what I&#39;ve been doing/experiencing this afternoon is a perfect example of that.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhpDeliciousClient, a php cli client to administer del.icio.us accounts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/phpdeliciousclient_a_php_cli_client_to_administer_delicious_accounts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2007 16:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/phpdeliciousclient_a_php_cli_client_to_administer_delicious_accounts/</guid>
      
      <description>PhpDeliciousClient is a console based client for doing maintenance on Del.icio.us accounts.
I wrote it because - to my knowledge - there currently is no good program (including the personalized del.icio.us web page itself) that lets you make changes to your del.icio.us data in a powerful, productive manner. (with data I primarily mean tags. Posts and bundles are considered less important).
You probably are familiar with the fact that a Delicious account (or any tag based meta data organizing system, for that matter) can soon become bloated: It gets filled with way too many tags.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhpDeliciousClient</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/php_delicious_client/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2007 13:52:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/php_delicious_client/</guid>
      
      <description>Introduction PhpDeliciousClient is a CLI program for administering your Delicous account. When you invoke it from the command line you have some methods to administer your tags and your posts.
It&#39;s written in PHP and uses Ed Eliot&#39;s PhpDelicous class to contact the del.icio.us api. (included in download)
PhpDeliciousClient is licensed under the GPL v2, while the PhpDelicious class is licensed under the BSD license.
Why? The main reason I started developing it is because administering your account on the del.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fosdem 2007 review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/fosdem_2007_review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2007 21:02:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/fosdem_2007_review/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every year, during a special weekend in February, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ulb.ac.be/&#34;&gt;University Libre of Brussels&lt;/a&gt; suddenly becomes a little more geeky.&lt;br /&gt;
It&#39;s that time of the year when many European (and some inter-continental) colleagues join us at&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fosdem.org&#34;&gt;Fosdem: the Free and Open source Software Developers&#39; European Meeting&lt;/a&gt; (more info &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fosdem.org/about/fosdem&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My favorite bash tricks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my_favorite_bash_tricks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2007 23:38:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my_favorite_bash_tricks/</guid>
      
      <description>Hello everyone.
This post is about bash, the shell providing so many users easy access to the underlying power of their system.
(not bash the quote database, although i really like that website too ;-) )
Most people know the basics, but getting to know it better can really increase your productivity. And when that happens, you might start loving bash as much as I do ;-)
I assume you have a basic knowledge of bash, the history mechanism, and ~/.</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
